[{"B": "the execution of the Chicago Seven", "question": "\"Standby, we've done praying.\" This famous quotation is attributed to the occasion of:", "C": "the invention of the telephone", "E": "the ratification of the Bill of Rights.", "D": "the completion of the Panama Canal", "status": "ok", "A": "the completion of the transcontinental railway", "answer": "A"}, {"B": "Japan", "question": "\u201cCivilization and Enlightenment\u201d and \u201cRich Nation, Strong Military\u201d were slogans used in the late 19thcentury by:", "C": "China", "E": "Russia.", "D": "Germany", "status": "ok", "A": "England", "answer": "B"}, {"B": "Successful talk-show host automobile repairmen.", "question": "\u201cClick and Bang\u201d is the name commonly given to:", "C": "Morse code by an old-fashioned telegraph key.", "E": "The automatic dial exchange.", "D": "The manual telephone exchange that was the foundation of the communications revolution.", "status": "ok", "A": "Early American cowboys that were changed to Ranchers by barbed wire.", "answer": "E"}, {"B": "negative", "question": "\u201cElectron\u201d came from the Greek word for:", "C": "amber", "E": "ivory.", "D": "the color yellow", "status": "ok", "A": "electricity", "answer": "C"}, {"B": "Eli Whitney", "question": "\u201cEverything can be done faster and better.\u201d This saying is attributed to:", "C": "Edison", "E": "Benjamin Franklin.", "D": "Taylor", "status": "ok", "A": "Ford", "answer": "A"}, {"B": "Scientists are not concerned with material goods.", "question": "\u201cThe Lunar Society\u201d was an organization that believed:", "C": "The good life is based on having adequate material goods.", "D": "Reaching the moon would stimulate the U.S. economy.", "status": "ok", "A": "The lunar calendar was good for agriculture.", "answer": "C"}, {"B": "telegraph", "question": "A certain inventor got the nickname \u201cwizard of Menlo Park\u201d as a result of his invention of:", "C": "motion pictures", "E": "stock ticker.", "D": "phonograph", "status": "ok", "A": "electric light", "answer": "D"}, {"B": "elevators.", "question": "A key to deep coal mining success in England was the invention of:", "C": "a better pick.", "E": "individual oxygen supplies for each miner.", "D": "electric engines.", "status": "ok", "A": "water pumps.", "answer": "A"}, {"B": "planned obsolescence", "question": "A theme of Pigeon Impossible was:", "C": "unintended consequences", "E": "the beauty of nature", "D": "waterfowl forever", "status": "ok", "A": "save the pigeons", "answer": "C"}, {"B": "There is still hope for maintaining a good quality of life if we maintain our respect for the Earth.", "question": "A view expressed in Maxidiwiac is that:", "C": "This is not true. The three films each present significantly different points of view.", "D": "none of the above.", "status": "ok", "A": "The damage to Earth is already beyond the control of humankind and decline in our quality of life is inevitable.", "answer": "B"}, {"B": "the church", "question": "According to Alistair Cooke, in the \u201cHeartland\u201d of the 19th-Century U.S., the cultural center was:", "C": "the school", "D": "Abilene, Kansas", "status": "ok", "A": "the mother", "answer": "A"}, {"B": "the French.", "question": "According to Bronowski, the steam-powered railroad engine was the invention of", "C": "the Polish.", "D": "the Americans.", "status": "ok", "A": "the British.", "answer": "A"}, {"B": "J.J. Thomson", "question": "According to Bronowski, this person was the inventor of the steam locomotive:", "C": "Marten Triewald", "E": "Richard Trevithick", "D": "Nikolai Slavyanov", "status": "ok", "A": "Nikola Tesla", "answer": "E"}, {"B": "political unrest", "question": "According to Chaplin, this was at the heart of America\u2019s economic problems in the 1930\u2019s:", "C": "social confusion", "D": "technological decline", "status": "ok", "A": "technological unemployment - machines taking jobs.", "answer": "A"}, {"B": "Washington", "question": "According to Cooke, this was the central city of colonial America:", "C": "Philadelphia", "E": "Boston.", "D": "Jamestown", "status": "ok", "A": "Williamsburg", "answer": "C"}, {"B": "public works and industrial development", "question": "According to Jacob Bronowski, in the 18th century English inventors and engineers were leaders in:", "C": "export of technological know-how worldwide.", "D": "the development of thrashing machines.", "status": "ok", "A": "automatic devices", "answer": "B"}, {"B": "public works and industrial development", "question": "According to Jacob Bronowski, in the 18th century French and Swiss inventors and engineers were leaders in", "C": "export of technological know-how worldwide.", "D": "the development of thrashing machines.", "status": "ok", "A": "automatic devices", "answer": "A"}, {"B": "poverty of the working poor", "question": "According to Modern Times, this (these) was (were) not part of America\u2019s problems in the 1930\u2019s:", "C": "social confusion", "D": "technological decline.", "status": "ok", "A": "technological unemployment - machines taking jobs.", "answer": "D"}, {"B": "puts greater emphasis on human concerns than usually happened in the past, but without sacrificing good scientific principles.", "question": "According to Rogers, a holistic approach to technology or engineering design:", "C": "would emphasize a broader base of social concern and design based on a blessed human instinct.", "E": "none of the above.", "D": "would root engineering design on a comprehensive sociological study of human convictions.", "status": "ok", "A": "would place greater emphasis on science and mathematics.", "answer": "B"}, {"B": "was developed by another company.", "question": "According to Rogers, some businesses fund essential product development by selling a product that", "C": "they know to be inadequate.", "D": "A and C above.", "status": "ok", "A": "contributes heavily to environmental pollution.", "answer": "D"}, {"B": "shaky", "question": "According to Rogers, the marriage between science and engineering is:", "C": "about to occur", "D": "dangerous to religion and society", "status": "ok", "A": "permanent", "answer": "A"}, {"B": "\u201cThere are practically no good theories today.\u201d", "question": "According to Rogers:", "C": "\u201cThere is nothing practical that can be easily characterized with theories.\u201d", "D": "\u201cPractical engineering makes little use of scientific theories.\u201d", "status": "ok", "A": "\u201cThere is nothing more practical than a good theory.\u201d", "answer": "A"}, {"B": "the cook\u2019s cabin on a steamship", "question": "According to Spiro Kostof, Catherine Beecher felt the kitchen should be modeled after:", "C": "the early Williamsburg design", "D": "the kitchen in the Hearst Castle", "status": "ok", "A": "the kitchen at Monticello", "answer": "B"}, {"B": "no technological problems being solved.", "question": "According to Volti, a lot of emphasis on principles and methods of science can lead to:", "C": "new scientific discoveries and a lot of new creative inventions.", "D": "restricted creativity and overly rigid approach to solving technical problems.", "status": "ok", "A": "the solving of all technical problems.", "answer": "D"}, {"B": "use of gold coins.", "question": "According to Volti, a significant difference in business practice between modern and primitive societies is:", "C": "production for a market rather than for the family.", "D": "merchants are preoccupied with the genuine needs of the customer.", "status": "ok", "A": "use of paper money.", "answer": "C"}, {"B": "done by individuals in fierce competition with their neighbors.", "question": "According to Volti, for most of human existence, work was:", "C": "driven by the profit motive only since this is the nature of the human species.", "D": "the shared obligation of the family or community.", "status": "ok", "A": "done by the men while women stayed home to care for the children.", "answer": "D"}, {"B": "Proof that engineering and science are threats to human survival in the world.", "question": "According to Volti, the tendency of science and technology to take nature as an object to be understood andthen conquered is:", "C": "Part of the general tendency of rationally oriented people to dominate their world.", "E": "None of the above.", "D": "Related to Rubinoff\u2019s \u201claw of the impossible.\u201d", "status": "ok", "A": "The central weakness of the western world in general and America in particular", "answer": "C"}, {"B": "computer maintenance.", "question": "Ada was one of the first to do:", "C": "computer manufacture.", "E": "none of the above.", "D": "computer programming.", "status": "ok", "A": "computer design.", "answer": "D"}, {"B": "Jones", "question": "After the American Civil War, this person designed improved gun carriages, turrets, and war vessels.", "C": "Latrobe", "E": "Eads.", "D": "Whitney", "status": "ok", "A": "Francis", "answer": "E"}, {"B": "involved only gathering of wild plants that existed in the river valleys.", "question": "Agriculture among Native Americans in what is now North Dakota:", "C": "involved fields of corn that were of moderate size.", "E": "None of the above.", "D": "A and B above.", "status": "ok", "A": "was nonexistent prior to the coming of Europeans.", "answer": "C"}, {"B": "design buildings whose walls were not load-bearing.", "question": "Albert Einstein worked with Ford to", "C": "invent steel for use in car frames.", "E": "none of the above.", "D": "develop safety glass for cars.", "status": "ok", "A": "introduce electrical machines to the assembly line.", "answer": "E"}, {"B": "design buildings whose walls were not load-bearing.", "question": "Albert Kahn worked with Ford to", "C": "invent steel for use in car frames.", "D": "develop safety glass for cars.", "status": "ok", "A": "introduce electrical machines to the assembly line.", "answer": "B"}, {"B": "tetrahedron", "question": "Alexander Graham Bell patented construction using what geometric shape?", "C": "sphere", "D": "pyramid", "status": "ok", "A": "cube", "answer": "B"}, {"B": "The \u201crude men of the back country.\u201d", "question": "Alistair Cooke claimed that the real heroes in the development of the U.S. were:", "C": "The minutemen of the Continental Army.", "D": "Inventor-statesmen such as Franklin and Jefferson.", "status": "ok", "A": "American politicians who had been educated in England.", "answer": "B"}, {"B": "Cow", "question": "Alistair Cooke claimed that three things were essential to the homesteader\u2019s life. One of them was the:", "C": "Buggy", "E": "Hammer.", "D": "Windmill", "status": "ok", "A": "Horse", "answer": "D"}, {"B": "Buffalo cakes", "question": "Alistair Cooke claims that homesteaders needed three basic items of technology in order to survive. Onewas:", "C": "A good load of fire wood", "E": "Barbed wire.", "D": "Sugar and salt for the long winters", "status": "ok", "A": "A good horse", "answer": "E"}, {"B": "Very little, since much of the auto industry had shifted its production outside of the U.S.", "question": "American experience in the automobile assembly line had what effect in World War II?", "C": "Substantial, since 80% of the entire war production was done by converted auto assembly lines.", "E": "Substantial, since 50% of the entire war production was done by converted auto assembly lines.", "D": "Substantial, since 20% of the entire war production was done by converted auto assembly lines.", "status": "ok", "A": "Very little, since it was hard to convert auto production to production of war materials.", "answer": "D"}, {"B": "1865-1875", "question": "American military forces were used against native Americans in South Dakota and striking workers inPullman, Illinois in this time period:", "C": "1820-1830", "E": "1910-1920.", "D": "1810-1819", "status": "ok", "A": "1885-1895", "answer": "A"}, {"B": "stone", "question": "American public works in the 18th century made heavy use of:", "C": "wood", "D": "an early plastic compound", "status": "ok", "A": "steel", "answer": "C"}, {"B": "phonograph, horse-drawn trolley, and train.", "question": "Among the early signs of modernization in Japan in the late 19th century were the:", "C": "phonograph, movies, and train.", "E": "education, full democracy, and women rights.", "D": "phonograph, movies, and transistor radios", "status": "ok", "A": "rickshaw, horse-drawn trolley, and train.", "answer": "A"}, {"B": "Jones", "question": "An accomplished engineer, this person was warm and gregarious by nature, published the results ofcollaborative research and trained a generation of younger engineers:", "C": "Latrobe", "E": "Eads.", "D": "Whitney", "status": "ok", "A": "Francis", "answer": "A"}, {"B": "racism in science.", "question": "An April 1993 issue of Science is devoted to:", "C": "the 500th anniversary of the discovery of America", "E": "women in science.", "D": "the 90th anniversary of the invention of the airplane", "status": "ok", "A": "the 100th anniversary of the invention of radio", "answer": "E"}, {"B": "To construct wooden buildings using very thick timbers.", "question": "An early fire protection technique used in the colonial period in America was:", "C": "To construct wooden buildings using thin sheets of wood so that one could easily break through the wall to escape a fire.", "D": "To construct wooden buildings only if they could be located with 100 feet of a fire hydrant.", "status": "ok", "A": "To construct wooden buildings coated with natural fats.", "answer": "B"}, {"B": "telegraph", "question": "An English editor wrote what follows in an 1835 magazine. It \u201cwill give anunnatural impetus to society, destroy all the relations that exist between man and man, overthrow allmercantile regulations, and create, at the peril of life, all sorts of confusion and distress.\u201d This editorwas referring to the", "C": "balloon", "E": "river boat.", "D": "machine gun", "status": "ok", "A": "railroad", "answer": "A"}, {"B": "axe", "question": "An example of an American tool that was developed by trial and error and also helped start America\u2019swood industry was the:", "C": "chainsaw", "D": "hammer", "status": "ok", "A": "Blanchard lathe", "answer": "B"}, {"B": "Teich\u2019s study of social groups", "question": "An extended treatment of the role of women in ancient Middle Eastern society can be found in:", "C": "Proverbs", "D": "Philemon", "status": "ok", "A": "Volti\u2019s study of social groups", "answer": "C"}, {"B": "Charlie Chaplin", "question": "Any discussion of movies and modern technology is certain to focus upon this person and the problems heencountered as a factory worker in the film Modern Times.", "C": "Buster Keaton", "D": "Frederick Taylor", "status": "ok", "A": "Mack Sennett", "answer": "B"}, {"B": "You have taken trouble with nothing in life except to oppress the poor.", "question": "Beaumarchais\u2019 charge against the noblemen of France was essentially:", "C": "You have taken trouble with nothing in life except to gain the King\u2019s favor.", "E": "You have taken trouble with nothing in life except to be born.", "D": "You have taken trouble with nothing in life except to deceive the King.", "status": "ok", "A": "You have taken trouble with nothing in life except to get rich.", "answer": "E"}, {"B": "human and animal muscle.", "question": "Before industrialization, almost all of the energy used came from:", "C": "burning of wood and other plant products.", "E": "none of the above.", "D": "all of the above.", "status": "ok", "A": "organic sources.", "answer": "D"}, {"B": "magnavox", "question": "Before it was known as the loudspeaker, it had which of the following names?", "C": "magnaphone", "E": "None of the above.", "D": "Extendaphone", "status": "ok", "A": "megampliphone", "answer": "B"}, {"B": "woofer", "question": "Before it was known as the loudspeaker, it had which of the following names?", "C": "magnavox", "D": "magnaphone", "status": "ok", "A": "telemegaphone", "answer": "C"}, {"B": "1760-1779", "question": "Ben Franklin\u2019s experiment with lightning to show that it was electricity was conducted in the period:", "C": "1780-1799", "E": "1820-1850.", "D": "1800-1819", "status": "ok", "A": "1740-1759", "answer": "A"}, {"B": "bringing the professional engineering skills of planning, organizing, and directing technical projects to America.", "question": "Benjamin Henry Latrobe aided in the transfer of technology to America by:", "C": "A and B.", "D": "none of the above.", "status": "ok", "A": "finding jobs for many skilled Europeans and Americans.", "answer": "C"}, {"B": "\u201cfather of agricultural engineering.\u201d", "question": "Best known for his invention of the cotton gin, Eli Whitney is commonly called:", "C": "\u201cfather of American technology.\u201d", "D": "\u201cfather of technology transfer.\u201d", "status": "ok", "A": "\u201cfather of Scientific Management.\u201d", "answer": "C"}, {"B": "Modern Times, New Masses", "question": "Between 1924 and 1926 Buster Keaton released two films which dealt with some major examples oftechnology.They were:", "C": "The Navigator, The General", "D": "Modern Times, Gone with the Wind", "status": "ok", "A": "City Lights, New Masses", "answer": "C"}, {"B": "High wages available from only part-time labor", "question": "Bronowski argued that the housewife of the last century benefited tremendously from:", "C": "Use of gas- or electric-powered refrigerators", "D": "Iron products for the home.", "status": "ok", "A": "Central heating provided by natural gas", "answer": "D"}, {"B": "gift of the Industrial Revolution was the emergence of the dignity of humankind while the contribution of the Renaissance was an understanding of the unity of nature.", "question": "Bronowski argues that the great:", "C": "mistake of the Renaissance was the invention of the idea of the dignity of humankind while the contribution of the Industrial Revolution was an understanding of the unity of nature.", "E": "mistake of the Renaissance was the emergence of the idea of the dignity of humankind while the the great mistake of the Industrial Revolution belief in the unity of nature.", "D": "gift of the Renaissance was the emergence of the dignity of humankind while the Industrial Revolution led to much confusion about ideas of the unity of nature.", "status": "ok", "A": "gift of the Renaissance was the emergence of the dignity of humankind while the contribution of the Industrial Revolution was an understanding of the unity of nature.", "answer": "A"}, {"B": "To fill leisure time especially during the long years in which they were confined to the caves due to the ice age.", "question": "Bronowski argues that the immediate ancestors of modern humans used cave paintings:", "C": "As part of ritualistic training and preparation for hunting.", "E": "To teach their people respect for all animal life.", "D": "To satisfy creative urges that were much more important than survival instincts.", "status": "ok", "A": "To leave behind a record of their culture and values.", "answer": "C"}, {"B": "invented the hearing-aid to improve his understanding of spoken French.", "question": "Bronowski claims that Benjamin Franklin:", "C": "didn\u2019t, in fact, make any significant contributions to the understanding of electricity.", "E": "none of the above.", "D": "didn\u2019t have any part of the writing of the Declaration of Independence.", "status": "ok", "A": "invented bifocals to improve his understanding of spoken French.", "answer": "A"}, {"B": "Steamboats.", "question": "Certain technologies have been heavily dependent on a multitude of minor improvements. Examples are:", "C": "Petroleum refining.", "E": "A and B only.", "D": "All of the above.", "status": "ok", "A": "Railroads", "answer": "D"}, {"B": "Aeronautical research", "question": "Charles A. Lindbergh received a lot of credit for his flight but thought that the flight should be credited to:", "C": "American aviation", "E": "None of the above", "D": "All of the above", "status": "ok", "A": "American industry", "answer": "D"}, {"B": "Aeronautical research", "question": "Charles A. Lindbergh refused to give credit for his flying to which of the following:", "C": "American aviation", "E": "None of the above", "D": "All of the above", "status": "ok", "A": "American industry", "answer": "E"}, {"B": "Businessman.", "question": "Charles Lindbergh was the son of a Minnesota:", "C": "School teacher.", "E": "None of the above.", "D": "Policeman.", "status": "ok", "A": "Congressman", "answer": "A"}, {"B": "work in developing scientific management", "question": "Charlie Taylor should be remembered for his:", "C": "early work in pioneering moving pictures", "E": "partnership with Bell in the invention of the telephone.", "D": "partnership with Edison in the invention of the phonograph", "status": "ok", "A": "early work on aircraft engines", "answer": "A"}, {"B": "Thomas Edison", "question": "Clyde Barrow was one of his great admirers:", "C": "Alexander Graham Bell", "E": "Orville Wright.", "D": "Douglas MacArthur", "status": "ok", "A": "Henry Ford", "answer": "A"}, {"B": "reaper", "question": "Cyrus Hall McCormick invented the _____________.", "C": "sewing machine", "D": "interchangeable parts", "status": "ok", "A": "telegraph", "answer": "B"}, {"B": "10 million tons of coal per year.", "question": "Deep mining in England around 1800 yielded about:", "C": "no coal. England imported all its coal from the U.S.", "E": "one million tons of coal per year.", "D": "no coal. England imported all its coal from Germany.", "status": "ok", "A": "10,000 tons of coal per year.", "answer": "B"}, {"B": "14 chromosomes", "question": "Domesticated agriculture has its origin in wild grasses. One of these was goat grass. Goat grass has:", "C": "16 chromosomes", "E": "an odd number of chromosomes.", "D": "28 chromosomes", "status": "ok", "A": "10 chromosomes", "answer": "B"}, {"B": "14 chromosomes", "question": "Domesticated agriculture has its origin in wild grasses. One of these was wild wheat. Wild wheat has:", "C": "20 chromosomes", "E": "an odd number of chromosomes.", "D": "28 chromosomes", "status": "ok", "A": "12 chromosomes", "answer": "B"}, {"B": "Government standards were not sufficient, and federal funding was not available.", "question": "Dr. Thomas P. Jones perceived two central flaws in the technical education system of the United States inthe mid-1800\u2019s. What were these two flaws?", "C": "Elementary school teaching created differences between private and open schools, and apprenticeship systems failed to encourage technological progress.", "D": "Technological teachers were not trained well enough for the growing number of these students, and teaching centers such as colleges were not large enough.", "status": "ok", "A": "The costs of this education were too great, and the length of class periods was too short.", "answer": "C"}, {"B": "1900-1909", "question": "During which period did the Model T Ford come into production?", "C": "1910-1919", "E": "None of the above.", "D": "1920-1929", "status": "ok", "A": "1889-1899", "answer": "B"}, {"B": "Minneapolis", "question": "Ead\u2019s Bridge was built in 1874. Which city is it in?", "C": "New Orleans", "D": "New York", "status": "ok", "A": "St. Louis", "answer": "A"}, {"B": "COBOL, FORTRAN", "question": "Early computer programming languages were:", "C": "B, C", "D": "MODULO2, PASCAL", "status": "ok", "A": "A, A++, B, B++", "answer": "B"}, {"B": "Bing Crosby", "question": "Early development of the VCR was financed by:", "C": "Bob Hope", "D": "Roy Rogers", "status": "ok", "A": "Gene Autry", "answer": "B"}, {"B": "hire a group of individual inventors and manage their work.", "question": "Early in his career Edison decided to:", "C": "identify a market before beginning work on an invention.", "E": "work only at the General Electric Research Labs.", "D": "work on projects that mainly interested electronics hobbyists", "status": "ok", "A": "work only on those projects he loved.", "answer": "C"}, {"B": "high-speed video editing systems", "question": "Early magnetic recording used metallic wires as the recording media. This technology is still found in:", "C": "fly-by-wire systems", "E": "videocassette recorders", "D": "underwater navigation systems", "status": "ok", "A": "flight data recorders", "answer": "A"}, {"B": "Argand", "question": "Edison and this person invented the light bulb at about the same time:", "C": "Tesla", "E": "Bessemer.", "D": "Fisher", "status": "ok", "A": "Swan", "answer": "A"}, {"B": "his hearing loss", "question": "Edison claimed he was helped in his work by:", "C": "his years of work as an apprentice to Eli Whitney", "D": "the support of his physician colleague Watson.", "status": "ok", "A": "the constant support of his first wife", "answer": "B"}, {"B": "telegraph", "question": "Edison had two children whose names honored which invention?", "C": "motion pictures", "D": "phonograph", "status": "ok", "A": "electric light", "answer": "B"}, {"B": "stock ticker", "question": "Edison\u2019s first patent was for a(n):", "C": "electric light", "E": "motion pictures.", "D": "phonograph", "status": "ok", "A": "electrical vote recorder", "answer": "A"}, {"B": "1,200", "question": "Edison\u2019s jumbo generators were each capable of powering this quantity of 16 candlepower lamps.", "C": "2,000", "D": "5,000", "status": "ok", "A": "1,000", "answer": "B"}, {"B": "his military expertise.", "question": "Eli Whitney agreed to a contract for producing 10,000 regulation muskets for Oliver Wolcott due to:", "C": "his financial struggle.", "status": "ok", "A": "his love for firearms.", "answer": "B"}, {"B": "automation.", "question": "Eli Whitney, as a weapons manufacturer, showed great talent in:", "C": "mechanization.", "D": "labor relations.", "status": "ok", "A": "subcontracting.", "answer": "A"}, {"B": "Western Union", "question": "Elisha Gray\u2019s idea for a telephone was purchased by:", "C": "Edison General Electric", "E": "Sony", "D": "General Electric", "status": "ok", "A": "Westinghouse", "answer": "B"}, {"B": "an ancestor of bread wheat.", "question": "Emmer was", "C": "a wild grass discovered by native Americans that revolutionized American farming.", "D": "an evolutionary failure since it had an uneven number of chromosomes.", "status": "ok", "A": "an engineer responsible for improving the production of steel in the U.S.", "answer": "B"}, {"B": "stone", "question": "English public works in the 18th century made heavy use of:", "C": "wood", "D": "an early plastic compound", "status": "ok", "A": "steel", "answer": "B"}, {"B": "Eckert and Mauchly", "question": "ENIAC was invented by:", "C": "William Shockley", "D": "Robert Noyce", "status": "ok", "A": "Tom Watson, Sr.", "answer": "B"}, {"B": "Japan invaded the Philippines and successfully pushed out the Spanish.", "question": "Fifteen years after Perry\u2019s opening of Japan to the United States and other Western nations,what had occurred?", "C": "A railroad was built connecting Tokyo and Yokohama", "E": "The emperor traveled to Washington for conversations with the president.", "D": "A bridge was built connecting oil-rich Battleship Island to Japan.", "status": "ok", "A": "A democratic constitution for Japan had been enacted.", "answer": "C"}, {"B": "McCormick", "question": "Following in his father\u2019s footsteps, this inventor developed a machine of tremendous importance infarming. His success in business and technological development led him to dominate his field, becomevery wealthy, and help fund seminaries.", "C": "Deere", "E": "Eads.", "D": "Whitney", "status": "ok", "A": "Jefferson", "answer": "B"}, {"B": "New Capital", "question": "Following the defeat of the Shogun's Army, Tokyo was designated the new capital. The word meant:", "C": "Who Cares", "E": "Northern Capital.", "D": "Eastern Capital", "status": "ok", "A": "New Way", "answer": "D"}, {"B": "He mistrusted the Jews but instituted incentives to employ the Blacks (African Americans).", "question": "Ford had this social view:", "C": "He mistrusted the Blacks (African Americans) but instituted incentives to employ the Japanese.", "E": "He mistrusted the Japanese but instituted incentives to employ the Chinese.", "D": "He mistrusted the Japanese but instituted incentives to employ the Jews.", "status": "ok", "A": "He mistrusted the Blacks (African Americans) but instituted incentives to employ the Jews.", "answer": "B"}, {"B": "The mathematical theory was too idealized or simplified.", "question": "Francis faced problems in applying the turbine theory of the day. One of these was that:", "C": "Friction was given too prominent a place in the analysis.", "D": "Experimental studies, though done properly, were not adequately understood.", "status": "ok", "A": "The mathematical theory was too complex. Even though the results were right, no one understood them.", "answer": "B"}, {"B": "break down motion into basic movements and to eliminate unnecessary motion.", "question": "Frank and Lillian Gilbreth\u2019s contribution was to", "C": "break down movements into basic motion and to eliminate unnecessary work.", "E": "none of the above.", "D": "break down work into basic traditional and rotational motions.", "status": "ok", "A": "break down work into basic motion and to eliminate unnecessary movements.", "answer": "A"}, {"B": "a centralized photo development system", "question": "George Eastman and C.E. Kenneth Mees created what in 1912?", "C": "the formalized industrial research laboratory", "D": "a school of camera lens design", "status": "ok", "A": "the formalized manufacturing system", "answer": "C"}, {"B": "Francis", "question": "He battled tuberculosis during his adult life:", "C": "Eads", "E": "Jones", "D": "Latrobe", "status": "ok", "A": "Bell", "answer": "C"}, {"B": "J. Frank Duryea", "question": "He believed that \u201cAll possible brain work should be removed from the shop and centered in the planning orlaying-out department.\u201d", "C": "Henry Ford", "E": "Frederick Taylor", "D": "William C. Durant", "status": "ok", "A": "Karl Benz", "answer": "E"}, {"B": "Clinton", "question": "He believes/believed that democracy may work best when concerns are close to home, and the individual isable to work in a local context.", "C": "Volti", "E": "Pursell", "D": "Reagan", "status": "ok", "A": "Jefferson", "answer": "D"}, {"B": "Francis", "question": "He called one of his first inventions a \u201csubmarine\u201d:", "C": "Eads", "E": "Jones", "D": "Latrobe", "status": "ok", "A": "Bell", "answer": "C"}, {"B": "Lincoln", "question": "He called the farmer God\u2019s finest creation:", "C": "Eli Whitney", "E": "Andrew Jackson", "D": "McCormick", "status": "ok", "A": "Jefferson", "answer": "A"}, {"B": "Melville Bell", "question": "He designed the \u201cVisible Speech\u201d system used to help the deaf to speak:", "C": "G. B. Shaw", "E": "Samuel Langley", "D": "S. F. B. Morse", "status": "ok", "A": "A. G. Bell", "answer": "B"}, {"B": "J. Frank Duryea", "question": "He designed the engine for the Wright brothers' first airplane.", "C": "Charles Taylor", "E": "Frederick Taylor", "D": "William C. Durant", "status": "ok", "A": "Karl Benz", "answer": "C"}, {"B": "Wozniak", "question": "He developed the first micrprocessor:", "C": "Jobs", "E": "Hoff.", "D": "Taylor", "status": "ok", "A": "Engelbart", "answer": "E"}, {"B": "Melville Bell", "question": "He had a major government contract to developed an airplane:", "C": "O. Wright", "E": "Samuel Langley.", "D": "W. Wright", "status": "ok", "A": "A. G. Bell", "answer": "E"}, {"B": "Wozniak", "question": "He invented the computer mouse:", "C": "Jobs", "E": "Hoff.", "D": "Taylor", "status": "ok", "A": "Engelbart", "answer": "A"}, {"B": "Carnegie", "question": "He is famous for subdividing assembly of his product into simple repetitive tasks:", "C": "Poulsen", "E": "Eli Whitney", "D": "Ford", "status": "ok", "A": "Albert Kahn", "answer": "D"}, {"B": "Francis", "question": "He pioneered business techniques such as credit selling and mass advertising:", "C": "Eads", "E": "Jones", "D": "Latrobe", "status": "ok", "A": "McCormick", "answer": "A"}, {"B": "Francis", "question": "He planned a ship-railway across the Mexican isthmus of Tehuantepec:", "C": "Eads", "E": "Jones", "D": "Latrobe", "status": "ok", "A": "McCormick", "answer": "C"}, {"B": "Wilkinson", "question": "He said that energy is eternal delight:", "C": "Franklin", "E": "Blake.", "D": "Wedgwood", "status": "ok", "A": "Boulton", "answer": "E"}, {"B": "Pursell", "question": "He said that many inventions are as pointless as going to the moon:", "C": "Cooke", "E": "Bronowski.", "D": "Kostof", "status": "ok", "A": "Volti", "answer": "E"}, {"B": "Ford", "question": "He said that the finest product of capitalism was leisure:", "C": "J. D. Rockefeller, Sr.", "E": "FDR", "D": "Kellogg", "status": "ok", "A": "Carnegie", "answer": "D"}, {"B": "Francis", "question": "He was a designer of ironclad boats:", "C": "Eads", "E": "Jones", "D": "Latrobe", "status": "ok", "A": "McCormick", "answer": "C"}, {"B": "Thomas Edison", "question": "He was narrowly defeated when he ran for a seat in the U.S. Senate and was a leading candidate for U.S.President in public-opinion polls for several years:", "C": "Alexander Graham Bell", "E": "Orville Wright.", "D": "Douglas MacArthur", "status": "ok", "A": "Henry Ford", "answer": "A"}, {"B": "Hoover", "question": "He was the originator of the statement concerning the United States: \u201cWe must be the great Arsenal ofdemocracy.\u201d", "C": "Roosevelt", "E": "Eisenhower.", "D": "Lindbergh", "status": "ok", "A": "Wilson", "answer": "C"}, {"B": "Boyden", "question": "He wrote about the history of river navigation in America:", "C": "Gould", "E": "Eads", "D": "McCormick", "status": "ok", "A": "Jones", "answer": "C"}, {"B": "Teller", "question": "He/she obtained a patent in the name British Admiralty for the chain reaction process:", "C": "Einstein", "E": "Curie", "D": "Szilard", "status": "ok", "A": "Fermi", "answer": "D"}, {"B": "Melville Bell", "question": "Hellen Keller dedicated her autobiography to:", "C": "G. B. Shaw", "E": "Samuel Langley", "D": "S. F. B. Morse", "status": "ok", "A": "A. G. Bell", "answer": "A"}, {"B": "were pioneering shipbuilders.", "question": "Henry Bessemer and Andrew Carnegie", "C": "helped found the University of Virginia.", "D": "supported Land\u2019s camera research.", "status": "ok", "A": "contributed much to the development of the steel industry.", "answer": "A"}, {"B": "the Gantt Chart.", "question": "Henry L. Gantt\u2019s greatest achievement was", "C": "reducing industry dependence on highly paid engineers.", "D": "firing any inefficient worker.", "status": "ok", "A": "founding Stevens Institute.", "answer": "B"}, {"B": "Hoover", "question": "His father opposed the U.S. entry into World War I, and this American hero opposed the U.S. entry intoWorld War II.", "C": "Roosevelt", "E": "Taylor", "D": "Lindbergh", "status": "ok", "A": "Edison", "answer": "D"}, {"B": "Jones", "question": "His ideas were probably shaped by his early association with Joseph Priestley and his practical interestswere shown by his involvement in a fire engine manufacturing firm:", "C": "Francis", "E": "Boyden.", "D": "Eads", "status": "ok", "A": "Latrobe", "answer": "B"}, {"B": "Francis", "question": "His invention was entered in competitions at international exhibitions in Europe in the second half of the19th century:", "C": "Eads", "E": "Jones", "D": "Latrobe", "status": "ok", "A": "McCormick", "answer": "A"}, {"B": "Private armorers excelled at ferreting out technical innovations created elsewhere.", "question": "How did arms manufacturers have access to the latest technologies in the 1820\u2019s and the 1830\u2019s?", "C": "Through regional organizations of technicians.", "E": "All of the above.", "D": "A and B.", "status": "ok", "A": "The federal government\u2019s insistence that contractors share information with the national armories.", "answer": "D"}, {"B": "One.", "question": "In 1800 about this many steam engines were available in the United States:", "C": "2 to 4.", "E": "200 to 400.", "D": "2 dozen to 4 dozen.", "status": "ok", "A": "None.", "answer": "C"}, {"B": "Francis", "question": "In 1847 he built a farm equipment factory in Chicago:", "C": "Eads", "E": "Jones", "D": "Latrobe", "status": "ok", "A": "McCormick", "answer": "A"}, {"B": "Argand", "question": "In 1856 this person invented a process for converting iron into steel on a large scale:", "C": "Tesla", "E": "Bessemer.", "D": "Fisher", "status": "ok", "A": "Swan", "answer": "E"}, {"B": "The Act of Preservation of Antiquities", "question": "In 1906 President T. Roosevelt signed into law", "C": "The Sherman Anti-Trust Act", "D": "The Universal Voting Act", "status": "ok", "A": "The Marshall Plan for Economic Development", "answer": "B"}, {"B": "transmissions", "question": "In 1913, Ford\u2019s assembly lines were producing:", "C": "magnetos", "E": "none of the above", "D": "all of the above", "status": "ok", "A": "motors", "answer": "D"}, {"B": "four-dollar, 8-hour day", "question": "In 1914, Henry Ford established the pay plan listed below, which more than doubled wages for a shorterwork day.", "C": "four-dollar, 9-hour day", "E": "five-dollar, 8-hour day", "D": "eight-dollar, 7-hour day", "status": "ok", "A": "three-dollar, 7-hour day", "answer": "E"}, {"B": "the diesel engine", "question": "In 1915, Peter L. Jensen and Edwin S. Pridham created what invention?", "C": "color motion pictures", "D": "synthetic rubber tires", "status": "ok", "A": "the loudspeaker", "answer": "A"}, {"B": "Packard", "question": "In 1952 this great contributor to modern technology said: \u201cAlmost anything that one wishes to do in theworld of today is made possible, or is done better, or is helped by electronics. Through its ability tocontrol, to amplify, and to convert between light, sound, and electricity, electronics provides a nervoussystem for our machine-age civilization.\u201d", "C": "Hoff", "E": "Vannevar Bush.", "D": "Wozniak", "status": "ok", "A": "Terman", "answer": "A"}, {"B": "steam engine", "question": "In Domesticating a Wilderness, it was said that John Deere invented what?", "C": "Virginia reaper", "D": "thrashing machine", "status": "ok", "A": "steel plow", "answer": "A"}, {"B": "Vigorously opposed modern science due to its damage to religion.", "question": "In lecture the instructor has:", "C": "Vigorously opposed technological progress due to its damage to human individuality.", "E": "A, B, and C.", "D": "None of the above.", "status": "ok", "A": "Vigorously opposed technological progress due to its damage to the environment.", "answer": "D"}, {"B": "a rural transit system.", "question": "In Philadelphia in 1798, Benjamin Latrobe presented the idea for:", "C": "an illuminated sundial.", "D": "a steam-powered waterworks.", "status": "ok", "A": "a mobile military group.", "answer": "D"}, {"B": "The Pentagon", "question": "In Pigeon Impossible, the intercontinental ballistic missile\u2019s assigned target was:", "C": "Tehran, Iran", "E": "The Three Gorges Dam", "D": "Bagdad, Iraq", "status": "ok", "A": "Moscow", "answer": "A"}, {"B": "Women focus more on scientific laws and less on individual subjects.", "question": "In scientific endeavors, according to Barinaga and Lebacqz,", "C": "Women are careful to stay detached from what they are studying and avoid the question of helping the object of study survive.", "D": "Women publish more but what they publish is cited less.", "status": "ok", "A": "Women have a capacity to empathize with the objects of their study.", "answer": "A"}, {"B": "Women focus more on gaining recognition of their colleagues and less on results.", "question": "In scientific endeavors, according to Barinaga,", "C": "Women seek collaboration more than men.", "E": "Women are more focused on \u201chot\u201d topics than their male counterparts.", "D": "Women are less likely to listen to all sides of a question and seek compromise.", "status": "ok", "A": "Women are more competitive and design instruction that is more competitive.", "answer": "C"}, {"B": "electricity", "question": "In the 1700\u2019s, what was the basic source of power for industry?", "C": "water wheel", "D": "primitive petroleum products.", "status": "ok", "A": "steam engine", "answer": "C"}, {"B": "Easter", "question": "In the 1880\u2019s, the Japanese government subsidized Mitsubishi, a private corporation, to build ships. As aresult, many people were forced to work in coal mines and live in terrible conditions on this island:", "C": "Midway", "D": "Battleship.", "status": "ok", "A": "Guam", "answer": "D"}, {"B": "Rural Electrication Board", "question": "In the 19th century this organization was given general federal responsibility for planning the constructionof canals, making rivers navigible, and planning for flood control:", "C": "Department of Transportation", "E": "Corps of Engineers.", "D": "U. S. Coast Guard", "status": "ok", "A": "Bureau of Reclaimation", "answer": "E"}, {"B": "automobile", "question": "In the early part of this century, this invention or convenience dramatically changed traditional livingpatterns to give women access to the modern world.", "C": "phonograph", "E": "electric light.", "D": "newspaper", "status": "ok", "A": "sewing machine", "answer": "B"}, {"B": "to develop photos", "question": "In the late 1870\u2019s a less perishable dry gelatin emulsion was created. What was the gelatin used for?", "C": "to clean metal parts in industry", "D": "to feed livestock", "status": "ok", "A": "to make a household food item", "answer": "B"}, {"B": "diesel engine", "question": "In the late 1930's, Chester Carlson endeavored to interest manufacturers in his:", "C": "color movie camera", "E": "none of the above.", "D": "molding machine", "status": "ok", "A": "typewriter", "answer": "E"}, {"B": "Between $10 and $50.", "question": "In the mid-19th century mass-produced plows sold for:", "C": "Between $100 and $200.", "D": "None of the above. They weren\u2019t mass-produced.", "status": "ok", "A": "Under $5", "answer": "A"}, {"B": "valued their labor and time immensely.", "question": "In the Middle Ages in a pre-industrialized community, people:", "C": "opened and closed their shops when they wanted and were not ruled by the clock.", "D": "charged a lot for time spent on products and work done.", "status": "ok", "A": "were governed by the clock and always on a set schedule.", "answer": "C"}, {"B": "Thomas Jefferson", "question": "In the video America by Design: The House, who is credited with designing the first kitchen reflectingdomestic science?", "C": "Frank Lloyd Wright", "D": "None of the above.", "status": "ok", "A": "Catherine Beecher", "answer": "A"}, {"B": "1910-1919", "question": "In which period did the first transatlantic flight occur?", "C": "1920-1929", "D": "1930-1939", "status": "ok", "A": "1900-1909", "answer": "B"}, {"B": "turbines", "question": "James Francis worked with and designed:", "C": "cotton gins", "D": "sailing ships.", "status": "ok", "A": "wooden plows", "answer": "B"}, {"B": "in Boulton\u2019s factory.", "question": "James Watt built his steam engine", "C": "in London in Holmes\u2019 Baker Street Factory.", "D": "in Lowell, Mass.", "status": "ok", "A": "in Philadelphia with Franklin\u2019s support.", "answer": "B"}, {"B": "China and the U.S.A.", "question": "Japan used newly acquired military power to commit surprise attacks on the naval fleets of these twonations. The first nation listed below experienced this in 1904 and the second in 1941.", "C": "Korea and China", "E": "China and Russia", "D": "Korea and Russia", "status": "ok", "A": "Russia and the U.S.A.", "answer": "A"}, {"B": "the seventh Russian vehicle to land on the moon", "question": "Jarvik-7 was", "C": "the mother ship for the first American lunar landing", "E": "none of the above.", "D": "an early English Hovercraft.", "status": "ok", "A": "an early Russian satellite", "answer": "E"}, {"B": "slaves", "question": "Jefferson believed that liberty would be threatened if individual families lacked:", "C": "citizenship papers", "E": "their own car.", "D": "private property", "status": "ok", "A": "sufficient children", "answer": "D"}, {"B": "12,000-15,000", "question": "Jefferson sold his own books to the Library of Congress. How many books were involved?", "C": "1,000-2,000", "D": "25,000-26,000", "status": "ok", "A": "5,000-7,000", "answer": "A"}, {"B": "industry", "question": "Jefferson thought that this was more important in a republic than in any other government.", "C": "education", "D": "capitalism", "status": "ok", "A": "science", "answer": "A"}, {"B": "the ratification of the U.S. Constitution", "question": "Jefferson's library formed the nucleus of the new Library of Congress on the occasion of:", "C": "the burning of the national Capitol in 1814", "E": "the burning of the national Capitol in Philadelphia.", "D": "the founding of the American Philosophical Society", "status": "ok", "A": "the Declaration of Independence", "answer": "C"}, {"B": "improved telephone receiver", "question": "Jensen and Pridham\u2019s original intent for their improved sound system was which of the following?", "C": "improved phonograph", "D": "sound motion pictures.", "status": "ok", "A": "radio speaker", "answer": "B"}, {"B": "lumber", "question": "John D. Rockefeller made the majority of his fortune by investing in:", "C": "petroleum", "D": "diamond mining", "status": "ok", "A": "steel", "answer": "C"}, {"B": "steam engine", "question": "John Deere invented the:", "C": "Virginia reaper", "D": "thrashing machine", "status": "ok", "A": "steel plow", "answer": "A"}, {"B": "they can be successful in a culture that understands that a different style doesn\u2019t mean reduced ability.", "question": "Karen Lebacqz believes that if women are given the opportunity,", "C": "they still will, ultimately, only be successful in traditional female roles.", "D": "they can offer the best contributions to society by following male role models and following the example of those women who have attained the highest level of success in today\u2019s world.", "status": "ok", "A": "they can perform the same job function as any man.", "answer": "B"}, {"B": "making the automobile commercially feasible.", "question": "Karl Benz is responsible for", "C": "the autobahn.", "D": "safety cages in automobiles.", "status": "ok", "A": "the invention of the automobile.", "answer": "B"}, {"B": "Taylor, Ford, and Bell", "question": "Kostof feels that any factory in existence today has a debt to these three:", "C": "Taylor, Ford, and Kahn", "E": "Edison, Parkard, and Bell", "D": "Packard, Ford, and Taylor", "status": "ok", "A": "Edison, Ford, and Bell", "answer": "C"}, {"B": "In steel.", "question": "Kostof referred to a different kind of organized labor as occurring:", "C": "In manufacturing.", "D": "In communism.", "status": "ok", "A": "In agriculture.", "answer": "A"}, {"B": "Kahn for his skill as an architect and Taylor as a contributor toward efficient use of labor.", "question": "Kostoff sees Ford as owing a debt to:", "C": "Wright as an architect and Edison as a contributor toward efficient use of labor.", "E": "None of the above.", "D": "Kahn for his skill as an architect and Gantt as a contributor toward efficient use of labor.", "status": "ok", "A": "Taylor for his skill as an architect and Kahn as a contributor toward efficient use of labor.", "answer": "B"}, {"B": "By being very successful dairy farmers.", "question": "Laplanders have survived through the centuries:", "C": "Hunting reindeer much like Americans hunt deer.", "D": "By following reindeer herds and harvesting the entire animal very efficiently.", "status": "ok", "A": "Raising reindeer.", "answer": "D"}, {"B": "help educators design curricula that are relevant to societal needs.", "question": "Lifelong study of the Impact of Technology on Society will:", "C": "help consumers make appropriate decisions in use of technology.", "E": "A, B, and C.", "D": "only A and B.", "status": "ok", "A": "help engineers design more successful and appropriate products.", "answer": "E"}, {"B": "About his wife and murdered son.", "question": "Lindbergh\u2019s book We was:", "C": "About himself and the Spirit of St. Louis", "E": "Never published until after his death.", "D": "About his partnership with Goddard", "status": "ok", "A": "\u201cGhost-written\u201d by his first wife.", "answer": "C"}, {"B": "air mail pilot", "question": "Lindbergh\u2019s first job was as a(n):", "C": "pilot in Byrd\u2019s arctic exhibition", "E": "clerk in his father\u2019s aviation business.", "D": "mechanic for Edison", "status": "ok", "A": "wing-stunter", "answer": "A"}, {"B": "11-20 feet", "question": "Mandan earth lodges had a diameter of about:", "C": "21-30 feet", "E": "51-100 feet", "D": "31-50 feet", "status": "ok", "A": "5-10 feet", "answer": "D"}, {"B": "Stone-Bird Woman", "question": "Maxidiwiac is a name that means:.", "C": "Buffalo-Bird Woman", "D": "Buffalo Skin Woman", "status": "ok", "A": "Big River Woman", "answer": "C"}, {"B": "No Japanese has any rights at all.", "question": "Meiji rule created a new political perspective in Japan which was described as:", "C": "We must all dance like the Dancing Cabinet.", "E": "Korea must be annexed!", "D": "Rich Nation, Stong Emperor.", "status": "ok", "A": "Heaven creates no man above or below another.", "answer": "A"}, {"B": "was Buster Keaton\u2019s last film.", "question": "Modern Times:", "C": "considers the plight of the assembly line worker and the working poor.", "D": "was the first appearance of Chaplin\u2019s \u201cLittle Tramp\u201d character.", "status": "ok", "A": "was Chaplin\u2019s first silent film.", "answer": "C"}, {"B": "help farmers in planting.", "question": "Motivation(s) for the development of the clock was (or were) to:", "C": "regulate the length of government meetings.", "E": "A and D.", "D": "regulate the irrigation of land.", "status": "ok", "A": "aid monks in scheduling religious prayers, masses, and other religious observations.", "answer": "E"}, {"B": "Old English for Navigation.", "question": "Navvies refers to", "C": "The worker who dug trenches or canals in England.", "D": "Small boats used for transportation along the waterways in England.", "status": "ok", "A": "Old English for Navies.", "answer": "C"}, {"B": "pony express.", "question": "News of the completion of the transcontinental railroad was communicated by:", "C": "telegraph.", "D": "telephone.", "status": "ok", "A": "radio.", "answer": "C"}, {"B": "the absolute subservience of women was divinely ordained", "question": "Nineteen-century North Dakota Native Americans shared this concept with ancient Hebrew culture:", "C": "the woman of the house held a key or central role in all of family life.", "status": "ok", "A": "religion was a minor part of everyday life", "answer": "C"}, {"B": "from the U.S. army of occupation", "question": "North Dakota Native Americans obtained their seeds for the coming year\u2019s crops:", "C": "from saving seeds from the plants they couldn\u2019t manage to eat.", "D": "from saving seeds from their best plants.", "status": "ok", "A": "from reservation seed stores", "answer": "D"}, {"B": "the first moon landing of the U.S.", "question": "October 2007 was the 50th anniversary of the:", "C": "the bombing of Hiroshima", "E": "the introduction of the first pocket calculator.", "D": "the invention of the microprocessor", "status": "ok", "A": "first satellite put in orbit", "answer": "A"}, {"B": "1925 with the IBM typewriter.", "question": "Office mechanization began in:", "C": "1874 with the Remington typewriter.", "E": "1898 with the Remington typewriter.", "D": "1874 with the Burroughs typewriter", "status": "ok", "A": "1898 with the Poulsen typewriter.", "answer": "C"}, {"B": "the great risks involved in the creation and use of high tech devices", "question": "On the serious side, the theme of Pigeon Impossible was:", "C": "the fallacies in the evidence for global climate change as presented in An Inconvenient Truth.", "E": "none of the above.", "D": "both B and C above.", "status": "ok", "A": "government efforts to effectively control the populations of wild birds", "answer": "B"}, {"B": "one each ten days", "question": "Once a well-known American industrialist and his company gained some experience, they built ships for theU.S. during World War II at the rate of:", "C": "one every four days", "E": "100 each month.", "D": "one each day", "status": "ok", "A": "one each month", "answer": "C"}, {"B": "to return to the cultural values of the past", "question": "One hundred years ago there was a people\u2019s movement in Japan:", "C": "to reunite the country with China", "D": "to establish a modern democratic constitution.", "status": "ok", "A": "to restore the emperor as a god", "answer": "D"}, {"B": "Mason", "question": "Over and over again, this person wrote of the essential \u201cgoodness and wisdom\u201d of the common people.", "C": "Madison", "E": "None of the above.", "D": "Hamilton", "status": "ok", "A": "Jefferson.", "answer": "A"}, {"B": "kidney dialysis machine", "question": "Paul Zoll was the inventor of an early", "C": "automatic transmission", "E": "pacemaker.", "D": "electric car starter", "status": "ok", "A": "form of television", "answer": "E"}, {"B": "over the past two centuries due to acid rain.", "question": "Peat bogs in England died:", "C": "in the 1970\u2019s due to widespread use of DDT.", "E": "none of the above.", "D": "in the past half century due to nuclear fallout.", "status": "ok", "A": "in the 16th century due to drainage to make the elaborate canal system.", "answer": "B"}, {"B": "Fleming in the 1920\u2019s.", "question": "Penicillin was discovered by:", "C": "Kettering in the 1930\u2019s.", "E": "Freeman in the 1920\u2019s.", "D": "Fleming in the 1930\u2019s.", "status": "ok", "A": "Kettering in the 1920\u2019s.", "answer": "B"}, {"B": "medical treatment", "question": "Peter Jensen\u2019s career was in the field of:", "C": "construction", "D": "radio engineering", "status": "ok", "A": "cars", "answer": "D"}, {"B": "Edwin S. Pridham", "question": "Peter L. Jensen became \u201cinseparable friends\u201d with", "C": "Charles Pfeifer", "E": "Rudi Blesh.", "D": "George Grinnell", "status": "ok", "A": "Valdemar Poulsen", "answer": "B"}, {"B": "Scientific Movement", "question": "Pinchot was the architect of the:", "C": "Efficiency Movement", "D": "Conservation Movement", "status": "ok", "A": "Progressive Movement", "answer": "D"}, {"B": "cannot be found anywhere in Pre-Christian writings.", "question": "Possible references to early agricultural experiences of human beings", "C": "were purged from the Hebrew Scriptures by 12th century BCE city dwellers.", "D": "are found in Genesis in the Hebrew Scriptures.", "status": "ok", "A": "are found in the Book of Jericho in the Christian Scriptures.", "answer": "D"}, {"B": "A penny saved is a penny earned.", "question": "Priestley, the Puritan chemist and minister, probably invented the phrase:", "C": "The end justifies the means.", "D": "The greatest happiness for the greatest number.", "status": "ok", "A": "Things are getting better and better.", "answer": "D"}, {"B": "Near Lowell, Mass.", "question": "Pullman\u2019s company city was/is located:", "C": "Near Detroit.", "D": "Near Chicago.", "status": "ok", "A": "In Washington, now the site of Washington State University.", "answer": "D"}, {"B": "conceived government's role to be that of disseminating information useful to the citizens rather than insuring material profit for innovators.", "question": "Regarding technological advances, Jefferson", "C": "denied government's role to be either insuring material profit for innovators or disseminating information useful to the citizens.", "E": "none of the above.", "D": "conceived government's role to be insuring material profit for innovators rather than that of disseminating information useful to the citizens.", "status": "ok", "A": "disliked the government's role in disseminating information useful to the citizens", "answer": "B"}, {"B": "Catherine Beecher", "question": "She became a writer, navigator, and radio operator when she married a Minnesota Congressman\u2019s son:", "C": "Susan Wright", "E": "Harriet Quimby.", "D": "Anne Murrow", "status": "ok", "A": "Amelia Earhart", "answer": "D"}, {"B": "Maxidiwiac", "question": "She believed that we would survive if we maintained our respect for the earth:", "C": "Marie Curie", "E": "None of the above.", "D": "Jane Goodall", "status": "ok", "A": "Ann Carlson", "answer": "B"}, {"B": "were invented in America in the late 17th century.", "question": "Significant devices and techniques that had a powerful impact on American agriculture were the horsecollar, the heavy plow, and the three-field system of crop rotation. These devices and techniques:", "C": "were invented in America in the late 18th century.", "E": "were brought to American by the first European settlers.", "D": "were brought to American by Irish immigrants in the late 19th century.", "status": "ok", "A": "were gifts to American settlers from Native Americans.", "answer": "E"}, {"B": "was significant in ancient Rome. About one-third of the population was in slavery.", "question": "Slavery:", "C": "is an institution that had its beginnings in the Christian church.", "status": "ok", "A": "in the history of the world was most prominent in the United States.", "answer": "B"}, {"B": "The 1967 Middle East War", "question": "Some believe that this war ended when an American president threatened to use nuclear weapons.", "C": "The Korean War", "E": "The Falklands War.", "D": "The Vietnam War", "status": "ok", "A": "World War II", "answer": "C"}, {"B": "High-tech farming.", "question": "Some crops like coffee tend to deplete soil of its nutrients. Thus, in centuries passed, it was often raisedusing:", "C": "foraging.", "D": "the hunter-gatherer technique", "status": "ok", "A": "Swidden cultivation.", "answer": "A"}, {"B": "20 chromosomes", "question": "Some historians of science believe that by some genetic accident, goat grass and wild wheat combined toform Emmer. Emmer crossed with another natural goat grass and produced a still larger hybrid with 42chromosomes, which is bread wheat. Emmer had:", "C": "28 chromosomes", "E": "an odd number of chromosomes.", "D": "38 chromosomes", "status": "ok", "A": "16 chromosomes", "answer": "C"}, {"B": "loneliness is the price you pay for leaving rural life behind.", "question": "Soseki claims that:", "C": "modern times put a high price on loneliness.", "E": "he would pay any price for the benefits of living in modern times.", "D": "loneliness is the price you pay for living in modern times.", "status": "ok", "A": "modern times are the result of the loneliness experienced by great inventors.", "answer": "D"}, {"B": "the defeat of Japan in the Sino-Japanese War", "question": "Soseki\u2019s novel Kokoro lamented:", "C": "the defeat of Irokawa", "E": "the moral decadence experienced under American occupation.", "D": "the decline of Korea under Japanese rule", "status": "ok", "A": "the passing of the age of Meiji", "answer": "A"}, {"B": "Hewlett-Packard", "question": "Stephen Wozniak and Steven Jobs are responsible for starting which company?", "C": "IBM", "D": "Watkins-Johnson", "status": "ok", "A": "Apple Computer", "answer": "A"}, {"B": "the democratization of Korea", "question": "T. Roosevelt\u2019s involvement in the Russo-Japanese War immediately led to:", "C": "his Nobel Prize for Peace", "E": "World War I.", "D": "the Battle of the Sea of Japan involving the Great White Navy", "status": "ok", "A": "the bombing of Pearl Harbor", "answer": "C"}, {"B": "the insights of workers", "question": "Taylor concerned himself with", "C": "the wages of workers", "E": "A and C only.", "D": "all of the above.", "status": "ok", "A": "the efficiency of workers", "answer": "E"}, {"B": "Devised by Eliphalet Remington in the 1920's.", "question": "The \"QWERTY\" keyboard was:", "C": "Devised by Thomas Edison in the 1840's.", "E": "Devised by Christopher Scholes in the 1870's.", "D": "Devised by Christopher Robin in the 1920's.", "status": "ok", "A": "Devised by Christopher Scholes in the 1920's.", "answer": "E"}, {"B": "Computers", "question": "The \u201cAnalytical Engine\u201d was a step in the development of which of the following?", "C": "Assembly lines", "D": "Large scale construction", "status": "ok", "A": "Internal combustion engine", "answer": "B"}, {"B": "Crop agriculture", "question": "The 19th century Indians of North Dakota had technologies to deal with:", "C": "Clothes and footwear", "E": "Only B and C above", "D": "All of the above", "status": "ok", "A": "River transport of supplies", "answer": "D"}, {"B": "O. Wright", "question": "The Aerial Experiment Association was by a group of engineers including Glenn Curtiss along withinventor", "C": "Thomas Edison", "E": "Valdemar Poulsen", "D": "Alexander M. Poniatoff", "status": "ok", "A": "A. G. Bell", "answer": "A"}, {"B": "1790\u2019s.", "question": "The age of tech farming began in Europe and North America in:", "C": "1890\u2019s.", "D": "1920\u2019s.", "status": "ok", "A": "1840\u2019s.", "answer": "A"}, {"B": "telephone", "question": "The Brazilian Emperor Dom Pedro II saw a demonstration of this invention at the Centennial Exhibition:", "C": "movie camera", "E": "roll film.", "D": "public address system", "status": "ok", "A": "airplane", "answer": "B"}, {"B": "Believed that all men were created equal.", "question": "The British government suspected that the ironmasters of the eighteen century:", "C": "Should control the gold that belonged to the British crown.", "D": "Were withholding knowledge of significant inventions that ultimately led to the loss of the American colonies.", "status": "ok", "A": "Believed that England would be better off without the American colonies.", "answer": "B"}, {"B": "Poland", "question": "The Central Pacific portion of the first transcontinental railway was built largely by immigrants from:", "C": "Italy and France", "E": "Mexico and other Latin American countries.", "D": "China", "status": "ok", "A": "Germany", "answer": "D"}, {"B": "27", "question": "The constitution provided for a patent system, and, by law, the inventor was granted a legal monopoly for aperiod of how many years?", "C": "17", "D": "37", "status": "ok", "A": "7", "answer": "C"}, {"B": "breakdown motion into basic movements and to eliminate unnecessary motion.", "question": "The couple that inspired the movie Cheaper by the Dozen worked on improving worker efficiency throughthe approach described as follows:", "C": "breakdown movements into basic motion and to eliminate unnecessary work.", "D": "breakdown work into basic traditional and rotational motions.", "status": "ok", "A": "breakdown work into basic motion and to eliminate unnecessary movements.", "answer": "A"}, {"B": "the adoption of the Prussian Constitution for Japanese use.", "question": "The culmination of Meiji's transformation of Japan was:", "C": "the defeat of Spain in the Spanish-American War.", "E": "the invention of the transistor by Japanese scientists.", "D": "the defeat of Russia in the Russo-Japanese War.", "status": "ok", "A": "the building of the Tokyo Railroad.", "answer": "D"}, {"B": "The Age of Small Men", "question": "The decade of the 1920\u2019s was known by some to be the:", "C": "The decade when small was beautiful", "E": "None of the above.", "D": "The Decade of the Great Awakening", "status": "ok", "A": "The Age of New Leadership", "answer": "B"}, {"B": "Vietnam", "question": "The decline of this Asian nation pushed Japan in the direction of modernization:", "C": "Korea", "E": "China.", "D": "Russia", "status": "ok", "A": "Angola", "answer": "E"}, {"B": "Madison", "question": "The designer of Washington, D.C. was:", "C": "Spiro Kostof", "D": "Ben Franklin", "status": "ok", "A": "L\u2019Enfant", "answer": "A"}, {"B": "petrochemicals.", "question": "The development of the industrial revolution was heavily dependent on:", "C": "the French Revolution.", "D": "the clock.", "status": "ok", "A": "slave labor.", "answer": "D"}, {"B": "Bell", "question": "The dial telephone was invented in the United States by:", "C": "Marconi", "E": "Poulsen", "D": "Strowger", "status": "ok", "A": "Edison", "answer": "D"}, {"B": "Albert Laborde", "question": "The discovery of radioactivity by _______________ in 1896 raised to a critical level the question of justwhat was occurring within the atom or molecule.", "C": "Henri Becquerel", "D": "All of the above", "status": "ok", "A": "Pierre Curie", "answer": "C"}, {"B": "Russia", "question": "The early work of Francis relied on data on the strength of iron developed by engineers and scientists inthis country:", "C": "The Netherlands", "E": "U.S.A.", "D": "Britain", "status": "ok", "A": "France", "answer": "D"}, {"B": "20 years", "question": "The electric light had been worked on for about how many years before Edison began his experiments:", "C": "50 years", "E": "200 years.", "D": "100 years", "status": "ok", "A": "10 years", "answer": "C"}, {"B": "Eckert and Shockley", "question": "The ENIAC was invented by:", "C": "Eckert and Mauchly", "E": "Noyce and Mauchly", "D": "Bardeen and Shockley", "status": "ok", "A": "Watson and Mauchly", "answer": "C"}, {"B": "70 to 80 horses.", "question": "The first combines were pulled by:", "C": "5 to 15 horses.", "D": "30 to 40 horses.", "status": "ok", "A": "10 to 20 men.", "answer": "D"}, {"B": "Apple", "question": "The first commercial computer that used a computer mouse to give the illusion of an office on a computerscreen was manufactured by:", "C": "IBM", "E": "Altair.", "D": "Digital Equipment Corporation", "status": "ok", "A": "Xerox", "answer": "A"}, {"B": "Apple", "question": "The first computer popular with early computer hobbyists was manufactured by:", "C": "IBM", "E": "Altair.", "D": "Commodore", "status": "ok", "A": "Radio Shack/Tandy", "answer": "E"}, {"B": "U.S. Census Bureau", "question": "The first computer produced in the U.S. was ordered by (the)________________.", "C": "IBM", "D": "Great Britain", "status": "ok", "A": "U.S. Stock Exchange", "answer": "B"}, {"B": "Northern Europe", "question": "The first electric battery originated in this area around 200 years ago:", "C": "Southern Europe", "E": "New England.", "D": "Australia", "status": "ok", "A": "Far East", "answer": "C"}, {"B": "Magnavox", "question": "The first experiments with sound recording on plastic tape were done by:", "C": "RCA Victor", "E": "Magnetophone.", "D": "3M", "status": "ok", "A": "Edison\u2019s East Coast laboratory", "answer": "E"}, {"B": "the Russian Yuri Gagarin", "question": "The first human to travel in space was:", "C": "the American Alan Shepard", "D": "the Russian Gherman S. Titov.", "status": "ok", "A": "the American John Glenn", "answer": "B"}, {"B": "ITT Semiconductor", "question": "The first mass-producible monolithic integrated circuit was developed by this company.", "C": "Nippon Electric Company", "E": "UNIVAC", "D": "IBM", "status": "ok", "A": "Fairchild Semiconductor", "answer": "A"}, {"B": "Fairchild Semiconductor", "question": "The first mass-producible monolithic integrated circuit was developed by _____________.", "C": "Frederick Terman", "D": "Hewlett-Packard", "status": "ok", "A": "General Electric", "answer": "B"}, {"B": "Harris Ryan", "question": "The first triple-arched bridge across the Mississippi River at Saint Louis was designed by whom?", "C": "Elmer Sperry", "D": "James Eads", "status": "ok", "A": "Thomas Thorton", "answer": "D"}, {"B": "1775-1784", "question": "The first United States patent law was passed in the period:", "C": "1785-1794", "E": "1805-1814.", "D": "1795-1804", "status": "ok", "A": "1765-1774", "answer": "C"}, {"B": "Houston-Grand Island, Nebraska", "question": "The focus of 19th century cattle trade was", "C": "Abilene, Kansas and Chicago", "D": "Albuquerque-El Paso", "status": "ok", "A": "Dallas-Fort Worth", "answer": "C"}, {"B": "Whitney.", "question": "The following person can be thought of as the father of the military-industrial complex:", "C": "McCormick.", "D": "Latrobe.", "status": "ok", "A": "Franklin.", "answer": "B"}, {"B": "laziness", "question": "The Gilbreths had a special interest in reducing worker:", "C": "hours", "E": "none of the above.", "D": "fatigue", "status": "ok", "A": "wages", "answer": "D"}, {"B": "Completed in the 1920\u2019s through Federal financing.", "question": "The Golden Gate bridge was:", "C": "Completed in the 1930\u2019s through local financing.", "E": "Was rebuilt in the 1940\u2019s after being destroyed in a storm", "D": "Completed in the 1920\u2019s through a Federal-State partnership.", "status": "ok", "A": "Completed in the 1930\u2019s through Federal financing.", "answer": "C"}, {"B": "The conviction and death by hanging of 4 labor leaders", "question": "The Hay Market Square incident resulted in", "C": "The conviction and death by hanging of 8 labor leaders", "E": "The conviction and death by hanging of 16 labor leaders.", "D": "The conviction and death by hanging of 12 labor leaders", "status": "ok", "A": "The conviction and death by hanging of 2 labor leaders", "answer": "B"}, {"B": "hunter-gatherers who followed natural animal migrations.", "question": "The immediate ancestors of prehistoric village dwellers probably were", "C": "Ape-man tribes of Central Africa.", "D": "Mongol tribes of Central Asia.", "status": "ok", "A": "nomadic tribes that possessed their own herds.", "answer": "B"}, {"B": "saw their works receive wide distribution due their ability to transmit their works by wire (teletype).", "question": "The Industrial Revolution had a significant impact on the Romantic poets of the late eighteenth century andearly nineteen century. The poets:", "C": "joined with the Luddittes in opposing the evils of modern technology.", "D": "fought modern technology because it reduced the freedom of women.", "status": "ok", "A": "were caught up with the idea of nature as a carrier of energy or font of power.", "answer": "A"}, {"B": "began in the heavily populated cities.", "question": "The Industrial Revolution:", "C": "was begun in villages by craftspersons.", "D": "did not include textile manufacturing.", "status": "ok", "A": "was fought by the French and the Swiss.", "answer": "C"}, {"B": "Removal of the inventor\u2019s name from the company name leading to the name General Electric Co.", "question": "The invention of the electric chair led to:", "C": "Removal of the inventor\u2019s name from the company name leading to the name Westinghouse Co.", "E": "Increased positive publicity for the inventor\u2019s research laboratory and increased funding.", "D": "Removal of the inventor\u2019s name from the company name leading to the name Business Machines Co.", "status": "ok", "A": "Removal of the inventor\u2019s name from the company name leading to the name General Motors Co.", "answer": "B"}, {"B": "1926-1928.", "question": "The last model T came off the assembly line in the period:", "C": "1929-1931.", "E": "1935-1937.", "D": "1932-1934.", "status": "ok", "A": "1923-1925.", "answer": "B"}, {"B": "Ford", "question": "The last of the three major automobile manufacturers to sign with the United Auto Workers after thedepression of the 1930\u2019s was:", "C": "Chrysler", "E": "Nissan", "D": "American Motors", "status": "ok", "A": "General Motors", "answer": "B"}, {"B": "the anti-slavery areas of the North", "question": "The Luddite movement began in:", "C": "the U.S. automobile industry", "E": "the American shipbuilding industry at the time of the War of 1812.", "D": "the hosiery trades", "status": "ok", "A": "the railroad industry", "answer": "D"}, {"B": "inherently good.", "question": "The majority of people living in the 1950\u2019s felt that all of the technological advancements were", "C": "causing energy shortages.", "D": "none of the above.", "status": "ok", "A": "threatening the quality of their lives.", "answer": "B"}, {"B": "Napolean", "question": "The Meiji political planners modeled their government after that of which world leader of the time?", "C": "Bismarck", "E": "Ho Chi Minh", "D": "Gladstone", "status": "ok", "A": "T. Roosevelt", "answer": "C"}, {"B": "was much lighter.", "question": "The Model T, compared to the European touring car:", "C": "had higher ratio of horsepower to weight.", "E": "none of the above.", "D": "all of the above.", "status": "ok", "A": "was lower priced.", "answer": "D"}, {"B": "Jefferson\u2019s home built and designed by himself.", "question": "The Monticello was", "C": "an early ironclad gunboat.", "D": "the town in which Jefferson lived.", "status": "ok", "A": "a statue in Washington D.C.", "answer": "B"}, {"B": "Hoover Dam", "question": "The oldest surviving Ampex black and white videotape depicts:", "C": "Grand Coulee Dam", "E": "English Channel Tunnel", "D": "Santa Barbara beaches", "status": "ok", "A": "Golden Gate Bridge", "answer": "B"}, {"B": "Hoover Dam", "question": "The oldest surviving color videotape depicts the:", "C": "Grand Coulee Dam", "E": "Nixon-Khruschev encounter.", "D": "Kennedy-Nixon debates", "status": "ok", "A": "Golden Gate Bridge", "answer": "E"}, {"B": "A. Carnegie", "question": "The phrase \u201cThe man who dies rich dies in disgrace\u201d is attributed to:", "C": "J. D. Rockefellar, Sr.", "E": "Steve Wozniak", "D": "Bill Gates", "status": "ok", "A": "J. P. Morgan", "answer": "B"}, {"B": "Vietnam", "question": "The Portsmouth Treaty made this nation a vessel state of Japan:", "C": "Korea", "E": "China.", "D": "Russia", "status": "ok", "A": "Angola", "answer": "C"}, {"B": "copper tools", "question": "The principal result of the Neolithic Revolution was the invention of:", "C": "cave art", "D": "crop agriculture.", "status": "ok", "A": "iron tools", "answer": "D"}, {"B": "it was a primary fuel of this era.", "question": "The ready availability of wood gave the Americans advantages that have seldom been appreciated. Woodwas a basic foundation of the economy because:", "C": "it was an important chemical product.", "E": "A and B only.", "D": "All of the above.", "status": "ok", "A": "it was a primary building and manufacturing material.", "answer": "D"}, {"B": "Magnavox", "question": "The ring-shaped recording head with a gap to concentrate the magnetic field was invented by:", "C": "RCA Victor", "E": "Magnetophone.", "D": "3M", "status": "ok", "A": "Edison\u2019s East Coast laboratory", "answer": "E"}, {"B": "Neil Armstrong", "question": "The second man to walk on the moon was:", "C": "Michael Collins", "E": "Alan Shepard.", "D": "Edwin Aldrin", "status": "ok", "A": "John Glenn, Jr.", "answer": "D"}, {"B": "1840-1849", "question": "The Shogun's Army was defeated near Kyoto during this period. This was a major event in the inthe history of the modernization of Japan.", "C": "1850-1859", "E": "1870-1879", "D": "1860-1869", "status": "ok", "A": "1830-1839", "answer": "D"}, {"B": "an early camera", "question": "The so-called \"polygraph\" was much admired by an American statesman. It was:", "C": "an early lie detector", "E": "none of the above.", "D": "am early calculating machine", "status": "ok", "A": "an early copy machine", "answer": "A"}, {"B": "1949", "question": "The Soviet Union detonated their first atomic bomb in:", "C": "1953", "E": "1963.", "D": "1958", "status": "ok", "A": "1947", "answer": "B"}, {"B": "independent lives full of social and cultural involvements.", "question": "The spinsters of the early 1800\u2019s led:", "C": "nothing. This has nothing to do with this course.", "E": "were social ostracized and unemployable.", "D": "the development of the pro-slavery movement in New England in an effort to free themselves of the drudgery of textile industry work.", "status": "ok", "A": "lives of bitter loneliness.", "answer": "B"}, {"B": "spinster labor.", "question": "The Supreme Court at one time approved and later disapproved:", "C": "child industrial labor.", "E": "the view that technical progress is always beneficial.", "D": "freedom of religion.", "status": "ok", "A": "engineers in the military.", "answer": "C"}, {"B": "Russia", "question": "The transistor was invented by three scientists from:", "C": "Sweden", "D": "America", "status": "ok", "A": "Japan", "answer": "D"}, {"B": "iron", "question": "The type of clock that was the first to be mass produced and the cheapest was made out of:", "C": "wood", "D": "copper", "status": "ok", "A": "lead", "answer": "C"}, {"B": "sometime in the period 1901-1920", "question": "The U.S. Rural Electrification Administration was established:", "C": "sometime in the period 1921-1940", "E": "sometime in the period 1951-1960", "D": "sometime in the period 1941-1950", "status": "ok", "A": "sometime in the period 1880-1900", "answer": "C"}, {"B": "in Nevada.", "question": "The U.S. transcontinental railroad was completed:", "C": "on the California-Nevada border.", "D": "in Utah.", "status": "ok", "A": "in California.", "answer": "D"}, {"B": "Grant", "question": "The United States Military Academy was founded by which President:", "C": "Jefferson", "E": "Washington", "D": "Madison", "status": "ok", "A": "Lincoln", "answer": "C"}, {"B": "destruction by floods or enemies was common.", "question": "The winter lodges of North Dakota Native Americans tended to be temporary since:", "C": "not applicable. North Dakota Native Americans spent their winters in the South.", "E": "Both B and D above.", "D": "stampeding buffalo commonly destroyed them.", "status": "ok", "A": "destruction due to forest fires was a constant risk.", "answer": "C"}, {"B": "Blue Planet", "question": "BThe work of George Catlin and Frederick Wilson are significant components of the film:", "C": "Picture Power", "E": "None of the above.", "D": "Sweet Fresh Water", "status": "ok", "A": "Maxidiwiac", "answer": "A"}, {"B": "Catherine\u2019s early interest in hot air ballooning (invented in France a century earlier).", "question": "The Wright brothers interest in flying was sparked by:", "C": "The gift of a toy helicopter when they were young.", "E": "Their desire to compete for the $25,000 prize offered for a successful flight from New York to Paris.", "D": "Rebellion against a father who allowed them to have no interests outside of church and school.", "status": "ok", "A": "Susan\u2019s early interest in hot air ballooning (invented in France a century earlier).", "answer": "C"}, {"B": "85 feet in 6 seconds.", "question": "The Wright\u2019s fourth successful flight on December 17, 1903 was:", "C": "350 feet in 39 seconds.", "E": "None of the above. It happened in 1906.", "D": "None of the above. It happened in 1900.", "status": "ok", "A": "850 feet in 59 seconds.", "answer": "A"}, {"B": "1956-1960", "question": "The Xerox 914 was first available to the public in:", "C": "1961-1965", "E": "1971-1975", "D": "1966-1970", "status": "ok", "A": "1951-1955", "answer": "B"}, {"B": "Jefferson and Washington", "question": "These people were two of the signers of the first U.S. patent:", "C": "John Adams and John Quincy Adams", "E": "Jefferson and Franklin", "D": "Jefferson and Andrew Jackson", "status": "ok", "A": "Washington and John Adams", "answer": "B"}, {"B": "Boeing and Lindbergh", "question": "These two shared a fear of German military rocketry long before most other Americans:", "C": "Ford and Lindbergh", "E": "Goddard and Fermi", "D": "Goddard and Lindbergh", "status": "ok", "A": "Hewlett and Packard", "answer": "D"}, {"B": "Watson", "question": "This British inventor profoundly influenced the Industrial Revolution through his work in turning the up-and-down motions of a piston into rotation:", "C": "Watt", "E": "Hooke", "D": "Kay", "status": "ok", "A": "Holmes", "answer": "C"}, {"B": "Glen Curtis", "question": "This collaborator with Alexander Graham Bell was the first person killed in a powered airplane accident:", "C": "Samuel Langlie", "E": "T.E. Selfridge", "D": "A. Santos-Dumont", "status": "ok", "A": "John Daniels", "answer": "E"}, {"B": "Western Union", "question": "This company turned down a chance to buy the rights to the telephone in 1876:", "C": "Edison General Electric", "E": "Sony", "D": "General Electric", "status": "ok", "A": "Westinghouse", "answer": "B"}, {"B": "the analytical engine", "question": "This device introduced the use of punch cards for the guidance of an industrial operation.", "C": "the Ada algorithm", "E": "none of the above.", "D": "the McCormick weaver", "status": "ok", "A": "the Jacquard loom", "answer": "A"}, {"B": "polio", "question": "This disease caused the death of more than half of the Hidatsa tribe over a century ago:", "C": "small pox", "E": "whooping cough", "D": "meningitis", "status": "ok", "A": "tuberculosis", "answer": "C"}, {"B": "Latrobe", "question": "This early American leader in technology wrote that \u201cthere is scarcely any other subject so familiarlyspoken of , and so little understood, as the principles of mechanics, and one, therefore, in which quackery ismore certain of success.\u201d", "C": "Whitney", "E": "Jones", "D": "Eads.", "status": "ok", "A": "Jefferson", "answer": "E"}, {"B": "Mason", "question": "This early American politician felt that: \u201cthis American world is not for me.\u201d", "C": "Madison", "E": "None of the above.", "D": "Hamilton", "status": "ok", "A": "Jefferson.", "answer": "D"}, {"B": "Henry", "question": "This early designer of an Iron bridge nearly lost his life due to his activities in France:", "C": "Paine", "E": "Adams.", "D": "Franklin", "status": "ok", "A": "Burr", "answer": "C"}, {"B": "Jones", "question": "This engineer suffered from tuberculosis. It periodically incapacitated him throughout his adult life. Heclaimed that he couldn\u2019t die because he hadn\u2019t completed hisTehuantepec project.", "C": "Francis", "E": "Boyden.", "D": "Eads", "status": "ok", "A": "Latrobe", "answer": "D"}, {"B": "G. B. Shaw", "question": "This famous American received significant government funding for the invention of the airplane, but failedto achieve significant results:", "C": "S. F. B. Morse", "E": "Melville Bell", "D": "Samuel Langley", "status": "ok", "A": "A. G. Bell", "answer": "D"}, {"B": "Edison", "question": "This individual was well known for never doubting his own abilities and holding to the certainties of hisown opinions:", "C": "Lindbergh", "E": "Francis", "D": "Kreusi", "status": "ok", "A": "Whitney", "answer": "C"}, {"B": "Hussey\u2019s reaper.", "question": "This machine cut a swath 18 feet wide, thrashing, cleaning, and sacking grain as it moved along:", "C": "John Hall\u2019s thrasher.", "E": "The combine.", "D": "Whitney\u2019s cotton gin.", "status": "ok", "A": "McCormick\u2019s reaper.", "answer": "E"}, {"B": "Mason", "question": "This man claimed that if men were virtuous there would be no need for government:", "C": "Madison", "E": "None of the above.", "D": "Hamilton", "status": "ok", "A": "Jefferson.", "answer": "C"}, {"B": "Franklin", "question": "This man hoped to use his retirement years for the sustained study of natural science:", "C": "Washington", "E": "John Adams", "D": "Jefferson", "status": "ok", "A": "Hamilton", "answer": "D"}, {"B": "Franklin", "question": "This man was the best scientist of the group listed:", "C": "Washington", "E": "John Adams", "D": "Jefferson", "status": "ok", "A": "Hamilton", "answer": "B"}, {"B": "Edison", "question": "This man's advice to deal with the 19th century problem of crowding in American cities was to leave thecity:", "C": "Franklin", "E": "Washington.", "D": "Jefferson", "status": "ok", "A": "Ford", "answer": "A"}, {"B": "Taylor and Gilbreth", "question": "This nineteenth century engineer/designer team developed machine tools capable of producing largenumbers of pulley blocks for the British Navy:", "C": "Gantt and Barth", "E": "McCormick and Whitney", "D": "Brunel and Maudsley", "status": "ok", "A": "Eckert and Mauchly", "answer": "D"}, {"B": "Sinclair Lewis", "question": "This person criticized America in the 1930\u2019s for buying gas before buying food:", "C": "John L. Lewis", "E": "Will Durant.", "D": "Walter Reuther", "status": "ok", "A": "John Steinbeck", "answer": "A"}, {"B": "Steinmetz", "question": "This person had a zeal for electrical development and also insisted on the \u201cintegration of the resources of thesoil, rivers, and human knowledge into a policy for the nation.\u201d", "C": "Cooke", "D": "T. Roosevelt", "status": "ok", "A": "Edison", "answer": "C"}, {"B": "Teller", "question": "This person is considered to be the inventor of the hydrogen bomb.", "C": "Einstein", "E": "Curie", "D": "Szilard", "status": "ok", "A": "Fermi", "answer": "B"}, {"B": "William C. Durant", "question": "This person made major contributions in establishing the audio and video recording industry in the UnitedStates:", "C": "Jack Benny", "E": "Arthur M. Pedrick.", "D": "Alexander M. Poniatoff", "status": "ok", "A": "Charles Scholes", "answer": "D"}, {"B": "Catherine Wright", "question": "This person roots her understanding of the work of women in science as paralleling the concept of empathyas understood from moral development theory.", "C": "Ellen Swallow Richards", "E": "Eleanor Roosevelt.", "D": "Anne Murrow Lindbergh", "status": "ok", "A": "Karen Lebacqz", "answer": "A"}, {"B": "Lindbergh", "question": "This person took an early, personal interest in the work of Goddard:", "C": "Pullman", "D": "Litton", "status": "ok", "A": "Orville Wright", "answer": "B"}, {"B": "Benjamin Henry Latrobe", "question": "This person undertook the redesign and construction of the United States Capitol and the White House, aswell as the Baltimore Cathedral:", "C": "Benjamin Franklin", "D": "Eli Whitney", "status": "ok", "A": "Thomas Jefferson", "answer": "B"}, {"B": "Mason", "question": "This person was known as the \u201cfather of the dollar\u201d because of his advocacy of a decimal currency system.", "C": "Madison", "E": "None of the above.", "D": "Hamilton", "status": "ok", "A": "Jefferson.", "answer": "A"}, {"B": "Hoover", "question": "This person was responsible for building Grand Coulee Dam and the World War II Liberty ships.", "C": "Cooke", "E": "Jensen.", "D": "Taylor", "status": "ok", "A": "Kaiser", "answer": "A"}, {"B": "Susan Isaac", "question": "This poet later became an aviation pioneer:", "C": "Ellen S. Richards", "E": "Christina Dumont", "D": "Catherine Beecher", "status": "ok", "A": "A. M. Lindbergh", "answer": "A"}, {"B": "Whitehead", "question": "This scientist observed some years ago that \u201cto quarrel with technology is to quarrel with the nature of man--just as if we were to quarrel with his upright gait, his symbolic imagination, (and) his faculty for speech.\u201d", "C": "Burke", "E": "Bronowski.", "D": "Bigelow", "status": "ok", "A": "Mumford", "answer": "E"}, {"B": "Morgan", "question": "This son of a poor weaver became a giant in the steel industry and donated over 7,000 pipe organs and builtover 3,000 public libraries:", "C": "Vanderbilt", "D": "Carnegie", "status": "ok", "A": "Rockefeller", "answer": "D"}, {"B": "the execution of the Chicago Seven", "question": "This was the occasion of a newspaper report from a famous city in which it announced \"the annexationof the United States.", "C": "the invention of the telephone", "E": "the ratification of the Bill of Rights.", "D": "the completion of the Panama Canal", "status": "ok", "A": "the completion of the transcontinental railway", "answer": "A"}, {"B": "Springfield, Illinois", "question": "Thomas Alva Edison\u2019s main laboratory was located where?", "C": "Menlo Park, New Jersey", "D": "Menlo Park, California", "status": "ok", "A": "Nestor, Massachusetts", "answer": "C"}, {"B": "every family should have slaves.", "question": "Thomas Jefferson believed:", "C": "every family should own a home and their own plot of land.", "D": "every family should not have children.", "status": "ok", "A": "each and every family in America should have the same income.", "answer": "C"}, {"B": "socialism and science", "question": "Thomas Jefferson thought that a combination of these two contributed to the new sense of Americannationalism.", "C": "science and republican government", "D": "science and technology", "status": "ok", "A": "socialist government and technology", "answer": "C"}, {"B": "was designed by French architect L\u2019Enfant.", "question": "Thomas Jefferson\u2019s University of Virginia", "C": "was the first American university to offer electrical engineering.", "E": "Both B and C above.", "D": "all of the above.", "status": "ok", "A": "reflected his distaste for urban life.", "answer": "A"}, {"B": "for the common man.", "question": "Thomas Jones thought that journals of technology should be:", "C": "as technical as possible.", "D": "for private universities.", "status": "ok", "A": "for the elite.", "answer": "B"}, {"B": "U.S. Post Office", "question": "Thomas P. Jones was appointed head of what U.S. organization in 1828?", "C": "U.S. Department of Agriculture", "D": "U.S. War Department", "status": "ok", "A": "U.S. Patent Office", "answer": "A"}, {"B": "\u201cKnowledge Movement,\u201d School Act", "question": "Thomas P. Jones\u2019 idea of bringing basic scientific knowledge to the ordinary man of the early 19th centurybrought about a movement known as ____________ and this movement culminated in an Act from 1862called the ____________________.", "C": "\u201cPeople\u2019s College Movement,\u201d Morrill Act", "D": "\u201cPatent Movement,\u201d Discovery Act", "status": "ok", "A": "\u201cJones Movement,\u201d Education Act", "answer": "C"}, {"B": "the cultural center of the USA.", "question": "To Jefferson the site of Washington, DC was best thought of as:", "C": "the political center of the USA.", "E": "the best site for his University of Virginia.", "D": "that Indian swamp in the wilderness.", "status": "ok", "A": "the historical center of the USA.", "answer": "D"}, {"B": "industrial combines like Mitsubishi", "question": "To modernize, the Japanese government of the late 19th and early 20th centuries fostered the growth of:", "C": "its military", "E": "none of the above.", "D": "all of the above", "status": "ok", "A": "public education", "answer": "D"}, {"B": "Astronomy", "question": "To which science(s) did the Greeks make notable contributions:", "C": "Optics", "E": "A and C only", "D": "All of the above", "status": "ok", "A": "Acoustics", "answer": "D"}, {"B": "Will it work?", "question": "Traditionally, a scientist\u2019s principal concern is:", "C": "Can I make a profit from it?", "E": "A and C only.", "D": "B and C only.", "status": "ok", "A": "Is it true?", "answer": "A"}, {"B": "Apple", "question": "Two of Frederick E. Terman\u2019s students formed what company?", "C": "Hewlett Packard", "D": "IBM", "status": "ok", "A": "General Electric", "answer": "C"}, {"B": "to record a dying person\u2019s will.", "question": "Valdemar Poulsen envisioned magnetic recording as mainly useful:", "C": "to record a politician\u2019s campaign promises.", "E": "to record the secret conversations of government officials.", "D": "to record popular songs magnetically instead of mechanically.", "status": "ok", "A": "to record business transactions.", "answer": "A"}, {"B": "tape recorder", "question": "Valdemar Poulsen won a grand prize at the Paris Universal Exhibition of 1900 for a device called the\u201cTelegraphone,\u201d an early forerunner of the:", "C": "telephone", "D": "record player", "status": "ok", "A": "telegraph", "answer": "B"}, {"B": "the Ampex system of video recording", "question": "VERA was the abbreviation used for:", "C": "Very Early Recording Apparatus (Edison's photoelectric recording system)", "E": "GE's Vision Electronics Recording Apparatus.", "D": "NBC Vision Electronic Recording Apparatus.", "status": "ok", "A": "BBC's Vision Electronics Recording Apparatus.", "answer": "A"}, {"B": "Impeded technical innovation.", "question": "Volti argues that the strong guilds in Europe:", "C": "Contributed to developing new professions.", "E": "None of the above.", "D": "Both A and C.", "status": "ok", "A": "Promoted technical innovation.", "answer": "B"}, {"B": "only slightly increases the amount of work performed.", "question": "Volti suggests that, in the absence of farm machines and chemical fertilizers, irrigated agriculture, ascompared to dry farming:", "C": "actually reduces the amount of work performed.", "E": "sharply reduces the amount of work performed.", "D": "has a negligible impact on the the amount of work performed.", "status": "ok", "A": "sharply increases the amount of work performed.", "answer": "A"}, {"B": "Both hated urban life.", "question": "Walt Whitman and Henry David Thoreau", "C": "Loved urban life and rural life, respectively.", "D": "Loved rural life and urban life, respectively.", "status": "ok", "A": "Both loved urban life.", "answer": "C"}, {"B": "Drinking and sanitation", "question": "Water used in the recent past neglected this use of water:", "C": "Irrigation", "E": "Recreation", "D": "Hydroelectric power", "status": "ok", "A": "Habitat", "answer": "A"}, {"B": "one-half", "question": "Water wheels as a source of power for industry early in the 18th century had a fundamental efficiency limitof approximately:", "C": "one-third", "E": "less than 10%.", "D": "three-fourths", "status": "ok", "A": "two-thirds", "answer": "A"}, {"B": "Robert White-Stevens", "question": "We will survive if we maintain our respect for the earth. This is the view of:", "C": "Maxidiwiac", "E": "None of the above.", "D": "Roger Christie", "status": "ok", "A": "Stewart Udall", "answer": "C"}, {"B": "measles", "question": "What caused the death of about half of the tribe Maxidiwiac belonged to?", "C": "smallpox", "D": "tuberculosis", "status": "ok", "A": "malaria", "answer": "C"}, {"B": "Post", "question": "What cereal company had a 30-hour work week for several decades?", "C": "Pillsbury", "D": "Kellogg\u2019s", "status": "ok", "A": "General Mills", "answer": "D"}, {"B": "Post", "question": "What cereal company had a 30-hour work week for several decades?", "C": "Pillsbury", "D": "Kellogg\u2019s", "status": "ok", "A": "General Mills", "answer": "D"}, {"B": "gender", "question": "What did Karen Lebacqz refer to as a social constructed category?", "C": "science", "D": "technology", "status": "ok", "A": "race", "answer": "B"}, {"B": "basic research seems to be significant as a direct source of innovations.", "question": "What did the authors of the study on the Queen\u2019s Award for Industry conclude:", "C": "long-term influences of scientific research were captured by industry.", "D": "little is known about the influence of science on industry.", "status": "ok", "A": "the great bulk of basic science bears only tenuously if at all on the operations of industry.", "answer": "A"}, {"B": "5th Avenue", "question": "What famous New York City Street was Edison\u2019s choice for his first use of artificial lights?", "C": "Wall Street", "D": "42nd Street", "status": "ok", "A": "Broadway", "answer": "C"}, {"B": "oscillation valve", "question": "What Fleming device was commercially used for the detection of radio signals?", "C": "vacuum jacket", "D": "outward-flow turbine", "status": "ok", "A": "storage battery", "answer": "B"}, {"B": "roll film camera with 100 exposures", "question": "What invention made George Eastman famous?", "C": "photography", "D": "radiotelegraphy", "status": "ok", "A": "glass-plate photography", "answer": "B"}, {"B": "steam engine.", "question": "What invention turned the cowboy into a rancher?", "C": "the horse and buggy.", "D": "barbed wire.", "status": "ok", "A": "the plow.", "answer": "D"}, {"B": "Luddites", "question": "What is the name given to people who see technology as a danger to society?", "C": "Communists", "D": "Scientists", "status": "ok", "A": "Jeffersonians", "answer": "B"}, {"B": "First large bridge that used steel as its principal structural members.", "question": "What made Ead\u2019s Bridge such a great engineering feat?", "C": "Arches were longer than any other built before.", "D": "All of the above.", "status": "ok", "A": "Piers founded on bedrock at greater depths than ever before.", "answer": "B"}, {"B": "Rutherford and Soddy", "question": "What two people found that a sample of radium maintained itself at a temperature higher than itssurroundings, which was peculiar?", "C": "Einstein and Oppenheimer", "D": "Fermi and Szilard", "status": "ok", "A": "Curie and Laborde", "answer": "A"}, {"B": "door-to-door sales.", "question": "What type of employment did the Industrial Revolution largely displace?", "C": "small business.", "D": "manufacturing.", "status": "ok", "A": "work in the home.", "answer": "A"}, {"B": "2\u201d x 12\u201d timbers", "question": "What type of lumber is used to build a balloon frame house?", "C": "2\u201d x 4\u201d boards", "D": "2\u201d x 6\u201d boards", "status": "ok", "A": "8\u201d x 8\u201d timbers", "answer": "C"}, {"B": "soccer.", "question": "What was Frederick Winslow Taylor\u2019s obsession?", "C": "being orderly.", "D": "money.", "status": "ok", "A": "cleanliness.", "answer": "C"}, {"B": "World War II", "question": "What was the great event that brought a halt to production and curtailed use of the passenger car?", "C": "The Bonus Army\u2019s march on Washington.", "E": "Increased train travel in the early 1920\u2019s.", "D": "The Great Upheaval", "status": "ok", "A": "Atomic bomb development drained the country of financial resources.", "answer": "B"}, {"B": "World War I", "question": "What was the great event that brought a halt to production and curtailed use of the passenger car?", "C": "World War II", "D": "The Dust Bowl", "status": "ok", "A": "The Great Depression", "answer": "C"}, {"B": "propel a boat.", "question": "What was the initial use of the steam engine?", "C": "pull train cars.", "D": "power the reaper.", "status": "ok", "A": "pump water out of mines.", "answer": "A"}, {"B": "because Jefferson supported the Navy and promoted the construction of 176 gunboats capable of defending harbors.", "question": "What was the main reason that the phrase \u201cJefferson\u2019s democratic sinking fund\u201d came about?", "C": "because Jefferson had many reasons for wanting to support communism and throw out democracy.", "D": "at the time Jefferson was President the government didn\u2019t have enough money from taxes to pay off the debts created during his term.", "status": "ok", "A": "because Jefferson hated democrats.", "answer": "B"}, {"B": "Tell the business owners that it was impossible to stop the flooding.", "question": "When James B. Francis was put in charge of rebuilding a system of dams and canals at Lowell, Ma., whatwas his method of dealing with the situation?", "C": "Seek solutions and then gather data to check if it would work.", "D": "Patiently gather data and then seek scientific solutions to the problem.", "status": "ok", "A": "Build up the dams immediately in time for the next flood.", "answer": "D"}, {"B": "Selfishness", "question": "D.When workers would deliberately limit their production to what they thought was fair, it involved what iscalled:", "C": "A strike", "D": "Justice", "status": "ok", "A": "A stint", "answer": "A"}, {"B": "machine guns", "question": "When World War II broke out, Goddard\u2019s desire to develop (the) _____________ was ignored.", "C": "large rockets or missiles", "D": "nuclear submarine", "status": "ok", "A": "F-2 bomber", "answer": "C"}, {"B": "machine guns", "question": "When World War II broke out, Goddard\u2019s desire to develop (the) this weapon was ignored.", "C": "large rockets or missiles", "D": "nuclear submarine", "status": "ok", "A": "F-2 bomber", "answer": "C"}, {"B": "France", "question": "Where did the Industrial Revolution begin?", "C": "Great Britain", "D": "Germany", "status": "ok", "A": "United States", "answer": "C"}, {"B": "Altamira, Spain", "question": "Where is the cave containing a 14,000 year-old painting of bison that was first discovered in 1879?", "C": "Lascavx, Spain", "D": "none of the above", "status": "ok", "A": "Madrid, Spain", "answer": "B"}, {"B": "Harpers Ferry", "question": "Which armory made the first regular-issue rifle to be mass-produced with interchangeable parts?", "C": "Middletown", "D": "Mill Rock", "status": "ok", "A": "Springfield", "answer": "B"}, {"B": "English Industrial Revolution", "question": "Which came first?", "C": "American Revolution", "E": "War of 1812.", "D": "Russian Revolution", "status": "ok", "A": "French Revolution", "answer": "B"}, {"B": "Magnavox", "question": "Which company provided President Woodrow Wilson a public address system in San Diego?", "C": "General Electric", "D": "Zenith", "status": "ok", "A": "Philco", "answer": "B"}, {"B": "The death of his father when his was 18 years old", "question": "Which event(s) led to Wilbur Wright\u2019s long battle with depression?", "C": "The loss of teeth in hockey and the death of his mother.", "E": "The marriage of his sister Catherine.", "D": "His horseback riding accident and the death of his father in the same year.", "status": "ok", "A": "The crash of their airplane in early 1903.", "answer": "C"}, {"B": "Catherine Wright", "question": "Which great woman of the 20th century authored North to the Orient and Listen! The Wind?", "C": "Ellen Swallow Richards", "E": "Eleanor Roosevelt.", "D": "Anne Murrow Lindbergh", "status": "ok", "A": "Karen Lebacqz", "answer": "D"}, {"B": "George Washington", "question": "Which important man in American history was given the nickname \u201cChild of Nature from the Backwoods?\u201d", "C": "James Watt", "E": "Tom Paine", "D": "Ben Franklin", "status": "ok", "A": "Thomas Jefferson", "answer": "D"}, {"B": "railroad", "question": "Which industry was on such a tight schedule the workers were required to have \u201cgood\u201d watches?", "C": "automobile", "D": "telephone", "status": "ok", "A": "steel", "answer": "B"}, {"B": "Dependent on tools and technologies.", "question": "Which is not characteristic of human beings?", "C": "Gain and transmit knowledge.", "D": "Independent of tools and technologies.", "status": "ok", "A": "Create tools and technologies.", "answer": "D"}, {"B": "\u201cvacuum jacket\u201d", "question": "Which item did Alexander Graham Bell not invent?", "C": "telephone", "D": "telegraph", "status": "ok", "A": "probe that could locate bullets in a body", "answer": "D"}, {"B": "he was Director of Public Works in Philadelphia", "question": "Which of the following are true statements about Morris L. Cooke:", "C": "president Roosevelt appointed him to head the REA", "E": "none of the above", "D": "all of the above", "status": "ok", "A": "he was a Progressive", "answer": "D"}, {"B": "automobile", "question": "Which of the following did Edison (with Kreusi) invent?", "C": "phonograph", "E": "None of the above.", "D": "A and C", "status": "ok", "A": "telegraph", "answer": "C"}, {"B": "Bicycle, automobile and other industries.", "question": "Which of the following did the invention of the sewing machine influence?", "C": "The garment trade.", "E": "None of the above.", "D": "All of the above.", "status": "ok", "A": "The role and status of women.", "answer": "D"}, {"B": "He was known for his talent of lecturing on various aspects of science and its applications.", "question": "Which of the following is NOT true about Thomas P. Jones?", "C": "He developed many new inventions in electrical communications including the loudspeaker.", "D": "He became the editor of the Franklin Institute\u2019s Magazine which later led him to be appointed head of the U.S. Patent Office.", "status": "ok", "A": "He was born and educated in England.", "answer": "C"}, {"B": "He was known for his talent of lecturing on various aspects of science and its applications.", "question": "Which of the following is NOT true about Thomas P. Jones?", "C": "He developed many new inventions in electrical communications including the loudspeaker.", "D": "He was the editor of the Franklin Institute\u2019s Magazine.", "status": "ok", "A": "He was born and educated in England.", "answer": "C"}, {"B": "First large bridge that used steel in its principal structural members.", "question": "Which of the following made the Eads Bridge such a great engineering feat?", "C": "Arches were shorter than any other built before.", "E": "None of the above.", "D": "All of the above.", "status": "ok", "A": "Piers founded on shallow floats.", "answer": "B"}, {"B": "She was born in 1842 in a small New England village.", "question": "Which of the following statements is true about Ellen Swallow Richards?", "C": "She was the first appointed female instructor-in sanitary chemistry and assistant in the laboratory for the chemical study of sanitation at MIT.", "E": "All of the above.", "D": "She campaigned to have domestic science included in the curriculum of the Boston high schools.", "status": "ok", "A": "She was the first woman to attend Massachusetts Institute of Technology.", "answer": "E"}, {"B": "Whitney was popular with employees.", "question": "Which of the following was a characteristic of Whitney\u2019s Mill Rock Armory?", "C": "Very uniform parts produced.", "D": "All of the above.", "status": "ok", "A": "A high labor turnover.", "answer": "A"}, {"B": "Navigation", "question": "Which of the following was not a major theme of the water conservation movement?", "C": "Fishing", "D": "Hydroelectric power", "status": "ok", "A": "Irrigation", "answer": "C"}, {"B": "Charles E. and J. Frank Duryea", "question": "Which of the two men were credited with building the first successful American gasoline-powered car in1893?", "C": "Henry Ford and son Edsel", "D": "William C. Durant and Reynold M. Wik", "status": "ok", "A": "Emill Constant Levassor and Karl Benz", "answer": "B"}, {"B": "She had a stable marriage.", "question": "Which of these statements about Ellen Swallow Richards is not true?", "C": "She was a founder of sanitary engineering.", "E": "She worked hard to oppose the domestic science movement.", "D": "She wrote correspondence courses.", "status": "ok", "A": "She was MIT\u2019s first female instructor.", "answer": "E"}, {"B": "Peter L. Jensen", "question": "Which one of the following is usually identified with the \u201cconservation movement\u201d of the early 1900\u2019s?", "C": "Gifford Pinchot", "D": "Ellen Swallow Richards", "status": "ok", "A": "Frederick Winslow Taylor", "answer": "C"}, {"B": "Gunboat", "question": "While James Buchanan Eads was serving as a clerk on a boat in the Mississippi River, what did he design?", "C": "A New Steam Engine", "D": "Diving-bell", "status": "ok", "A": "A bridge", "answer": "D"}, {"B": "Uriah A. Boyden", "question": "Who assumed the presidency of the National Geographic Society in 1897 on the death of GardinerHubbard? This person is also responsible for the popularity of the National Geographic Magazine.", "C": "Samuel Howd", "D": "Alexander Graham Bell", "status": "ok", "A": "Charles Pfeifer", "answer": "D"}, {"B": "Meiji", "question": "Who became the first prime minister of Japan during the Meiji revolution?", "C": "Okata", "E": "None of the above", "D": "Ito", "status": "ok", "A": "Sakomoyo", "answer": "D"}, {"B": "James Madison", "question": "Who believed that inventions were a cumulative process rather than a single fruit of genius, and thereforedisapproved of a monopoly patent grant on inventions because he believed that it was restricting to thefreedom of ideas?", "C": "Ben Franklin", "D": "George Washington", "status": "ok", "A": "Thomas Jefferson", "answer": "A"}, {"B": "Ford", "question": "Who created a system of greater industrial efficiency, called Scientific Management?", "C": "Durant", "D": "Taylor", "status": "ok", "A": "Carnegie", "answer": "D"}, {"B": "Noyce and Kilby", "question": "Who developed the first integrated circuit?", "C": "Lee and Jones", "D": "Thomas and Topp", "status": "ok", "A": "Jones and Earl", "answer": "B"}, {"B": "Jefferson", "question": "Who discovered that the pendulum could be used in a clock?", "C": "Galileo", "D": "Newton", "status": "ok", "A": "Ben Franklin", "answer": "C"}, {"B": "Samuel Langley", "question": "Who filed a \u201cstatement of conception\u201d for a telephone device only hours after Alexander Graham Belldid?", "C": "Gardiner Greene Hubbard", "D": "Elisha Gray", "status": "ok", "A": "Samuel F.B. Morse", "answer": "D"}, {"B": "Durant", "question": "Who founded General Motors?", "C": "Galbraith", "D": "Taylor", "status": "ok", "A": "Ford", "answer": "B"}, {"B": "Cooke", "question": "Who had great influence in the development of electricity for rural areas?", "C": "Eads", "D": "Pinchot", "status": "ok", "A": "Edison", "answer": "B"}, {"B": "Ann Murrow", "question": "Who is credited with designing the first kitchen reflecting domestic science?", "C": "Frank Lloyd Wright", "D": "Elizabeth Wright", "status": "ok", "A": "Catherine Beecher", "answer": "A"}, {"B": "Valdemar Poulsen", "question": "Who is credited with the start and development of Silicon Valley?", "C": "Frederick Terman", "D": "Peter Jensen", "status": "ok", "A": "Edwin S. Pridham", "answer": "C"}, {"B": "Carlson", "question": "Who is reputed to have said that he could see farther because he stood on the shoulders of giants?", "C": "Rogers", "D": "Aiken", "status": "ok", "A": "Newton", "answer": "A"}, {"B": "Edgar Allan Poe", "question": "Who rates as one of the most prolific American inventors and was called the American Hero of the GildedAge?", "C": "Thomas Alva Edison", "D": "Thomas Jefferson", "status": "ok", "A": "Eli Whitney", "answer": "C"}, {"B": "George Washington", "question": "Who received Eli Whitney\u2019s cotton gin patent application in 1793?", "C": "Thomas Jefferson", "D": "John Davis", "status": "ok", "A": "James Watt", "answer": "C"}, {"B": "Frank Gilbreth", "question": "Who took Taylorism to the U.S. Federal Arsenal in Watertown in 1909?", "C": "Henry Gantt", "D": "Carl Barth", "status": "ok", "A": "Frederick Taylor", "answer": "D"}, {"B": "Valdemar Poulsen", "question": "Who was at one time head of the Rural Electrification Administration (REA)?", "C": "Morris L. Cooke", "D": "Gifford Pinchot", "status": "ok", "A": "Harold L. Ickes", "answer": "C"}, {"B": "Cary Wolinsky", "question": "Who was Karl Marx\u2019s collaborator and a strong advocate of the rights of working people?", "C": "Henry Davidson", "D": "Stephen A. Burke", "status": "ok", "A": "Fredrick Engels", "answer": "A"}, {"B": "Chamberlin", "question": "Who was nicknamed \u201cThe Flying Fool?\u201d", "C": "Browne", "D": "Lindbergh", "status": "ok", "A": "Byrd", "answer": "D"}, {"B": "Ellen Richards", "question": "Who was one of the founders of the discipline of sanitary engineering in the United States and was alsoamong the first women in the U.S. to be formally employed as a scientist?", "C": "Susan Nichols", "D": "Lillian Gilbreth", "status": "ok", "A": "Catherine Beecher", "answer": "B"}, {"B": "Charles Lindbergh", "question": "Who was said to have opened a new \u201cfrontier\u201d with his famous airplane flight which represented anadvance into a complex industrial present?", "C": "Daniel Guggenheim", "D": "H.G. Wells", "status": "ok", "A": "Robert Godderd", "answer": "B"}, {"B": "Douglas", "question": "Who was the first professionally trained forester in the U.S.?", "C": "Garfield", "D": "Pinchot", "status": "ok", "A": "Roosevelt", "answer": "D"}, {"B": "Robert Fulton", "question": "Who was the inventor of underwater mines?", "C": "Eli Whitney", "D": "George Fleming", "status": "ok", "A": "Thomas Jefferson", "answer": "B"}, {"B": "Eastman", "question": "Who was the man who was concerned with communication and breaking down the barriers between peoplebecause both his mother and wife were deaf?", "C": "Bell", "D": "Jensen", "status": "ok", "A": "Edison", "answer": "C"}, {"B": "Robert Goddard", "question": "Who was the prominent Philadelphia resident who concentrated on how to realize the full potential ofelectric technology for society\u2019s benefit?", "C": "Morris Cooke", "D": "Albert Laborde", "status": "ok", "A": "Frederick Taylor", "answer": "C"}, {"B": "Helen Hayes", "question": "Who was the woman responsible for starting the American Home Economics Association?", "C": "Ellen Richards", "D": "Kate Smith", "status": "ok", "A": "Catherine Beecher", "answer": "C"}, {"B": "Chaplin & Rutherford", "question": "Who were the greatest silent film comedians?", "C": "Keaton & Laborde", "D": "Chaplin & Keaton", "status": "ok", "A": "Laborde & Rutherford", "answer": "D"}, {"B": "Ellen Richards", "question": "Who wrote the famous book The Jungle?", "C": "Upton Sinclair", "D": "Gifford Pinchot", "status": "ok", "A": "George Gastman", "answer": "C"}, {"B": "Their children would benefit from their efforts.", "question": "Why did the farmers of Japan work so hard to pay high taxes without complaining during the modernizationof Japan?", "C": "They wanted a say in the new government.", "E": "None of the above.", "D": "All of the above.", "status": "ok", "A": "They owned their own land.", "answer": "D"}, {"B": "kidney dialysis machine", "question": "Willem Kolff was the inventor of an early", "C": "automatic transmission", "E": "pacemaker", "D": "electric car starter", "status": "ok", "A": "form of television", "answer": "B"}, {"B": "Francis", "question": "With Boyden, he did all experimentation on full-sized turbines, circumventing the unpredictable results ofmodel experiments:", "C": "Eads", "E": "Jones", "D": "Latrobe", "status": "ok", "A": "McCormick", "answer": "B"}, {"B": "Swan", "question": "With the help of whom did Alexander Graham Bell develop the diaphragm used in the telephone?", "C": "Hook", "D": "Watson", "status": "ok", "A": "John Bell", "answer": "D"}, {"B": "Who cares!", "question": "With the Meiji transformation of Japan, there was an short era of confusion that swept Japan. It was knownby the phrase Eijaniaka, which meant:", "C": "Long live the Emperor!", "E": "None of the above.", "D": "Drive out the barbarians!", "status": "ok", "A": "Hippies all!", "answer": "B"}]
